<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">TourIndia</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
     <string name="search">search state</string>
     <string name="click">click here</string>
     <string name="link">"http://www."</string>
     <string name="go">GO</string>
    <string name="goldentemple">The Harmandir Sahib , also known as Darbar Sahib , and informally referred to as the Golden Temple, is the holiest Sikh gurdwara located in the city of Amritsar, Punjab, India. The city was founded in 1574 by the fourth Sikh guru, Guru Ram Das. The Harmandir Sahib was designed by the fifth guru, Guru Arjan, who had the cornerstone laid by the Muslim Sufi saint Sai Hazrat Mian Mir on 28 December 1588. Guru Arjan completed the Adi Granth, the holy scripture of Sikhism, in 1604 and installed it in the gurdwara. \n
	    		There are four doors to get into the Harmandir Sahib, which symbolize the openness of the Sikhs towards all people and religions.The present-day gurdwara was rebuilt in 1764 by Jassa Singh Ahluwalia with the help of other Sikh Misls. In the early nineteenth century, Maharaja Ranjit Singh secured the Punjab region from outside attack and covered the upper floors of the gurdwara with gold, which gives it its distinctive appearance and its English name. \n
	    		The Harimandir Sahib is considered holy by Sikhs. The holiest text of Sikhism, the Guru Granth Sahib, is present inside the gurdwara during daytime and the holy book goes for Sukhasan during the night time. Its construction was mainly intended to build a place of worship for men and women from all walks of life and all religions to come and worship God equally.Over 100,000 people visit the holy shrine daily for worship.</string>
 
     <string name="jallianwalabagh">"The Jallianwala Bagh massacre, also known as the Amritsar massacre, took place on 13 April 1919 when a crowd of nonviolent protesters, along with Baishakhi pilgrims, who had gathered in the Jallianwala Bagh garden in Amritsar, Punjab were fired upon by troops of the British Indian Army under the command of Reginald Dyer. The crowd had gathered to protest against the arrest of two nationalist leaders, Dr. Satyapal, Dr. Saifuddin Kitchlew, although a curfew had been recently declared. On Dyers orders, his troops fired on the crowd for ten minutes, directing their bullets largely towards the few open gates through which people were trying to run out. The figures released by the British government were 370 dead and 1200 wounded. Other sources place the number dead at well over 1000. This brutality stunned the entire nation,resulting in a wrenching loss of faith+ of the general public in the intentions of Britain. The ineffective inquiry and the initial accolades for Dyer by the House of Lords fuelled widespread anger, leading to the Non-cooperation Movement of 1920–22.\n
	   On Sundasy, 13 April 1919, Dyer was convinced of a major insurrection and he banned all meetings, however this notice was not widely disseminated. That was the day of Baisakhi, the main Sikh festival, and many villagers had gathered in the Bagh. On hearing that a meeting had assembled at Jallianwala Bagh, Dyer went with fifty Gurkha riflemen to a raised bank and ordered them to shoot at the crowd. Dyer continued the firing for about ten minutes, until the ammunition supply was almost exhausted; Dyer stated that 1,650 rounds had been fired, a number which seems to have been derived by counting empty cartridge cases picked up by the troops. Official British Indian sources gave a figure of 379 identified dead, with approximately 1,100 wounded. The casualty number estimated by the Indian National Congress was more than 1,500, with approximately 1,000 dead.\n
	   Dyer was initially lauded by conservative forces in the empire, but in July 1920 he was censured and forced to retire by the House of Commons. He became a celebrated hero in Britain among most of the people connected to the British Raj, for example, the House of Lords, but unpopular in the House of Commons, which voted against Dyer twice. The massacre caused a re-evaluation of the armys role, in which the new policy became minimum force, and the army was retrained and developed suitable tactics for crowd control. Some historians consider the episode as a decisive step towards the end of British rule in India, although others believe that greater self-government was inevitable as a result of India's involvement in World War I."
	  </string>
      
      <string name="wagahborder">The Wagah border closing lowering of the flags ceremony, or The Beating Retreat ceremony, is a daily military practice that the security forces of India (Border Security Force) and Pakistan (Pakistan Rangers) have jointly followed since 1959.The drill is characterized by elaborate and rapid dance-like maneuvers, which has been described as colourful and silly. It is alternatively a symbol of the two countries rivalry, as well as brotherhood and cooperation between the two nations.\n
	      This ceremony takes place every evening before sunset at the Wagah border, which as part of the Grand Trunk Road was the only road link between these two countries before the opening of the Aman Setu in Kashmir in 1999. The ceremony starts with a blustering parade by the soldiers from both the sides, and ends up in the perfectly coordinated lowering of the two nations flags. It is called the beating retreat border ceremony on the international level. One infantryman stands at attention on each side of the gate. As the sun sets, the iron gates at the border are opened and the two flags are lowered simultaneously. The flags are folded and the ceremony ends with a retreat that involves a brusque handshake between soldiers from either side, followed by the closing of the gates again. The spectacle of the ceremony attracts many visitors from both sides of the border, as well as international tourists.\n
          In October 2010, Major General Yaqub Ali Khan of the Pakistan Rangers decided that the aggressive aspect of the ceremonial theatrics should be toned down.The ceremony has been filmed and broadcast by Michael Palin for one of his television around-the-world travel programs; he described it as a display of carefully choreographed contempt.
      </string>
      
      <string name="rockgarden">"The Rock Garden of Chandigarh is a sculpture garden in Chandigarh, India, also known as Nek Chand's Rock Garden after its founder Nek Chand, a government official who started the garden secretly in his spare time in 1957. Today it is spread over an area of 40 acres (160,000 m²). It is completely built of industrial and home waste and thrown-away items.\n
          It is near Sukhna Lake. It consists of man-made interlinked waterfalls and many other sculptures that have been made of scrap and other kinds of wastes (bottles, glasses, bangles, tiles, ceramic pots, sinks, electrical waste, etc.) which are placed in walled paths.\n
          In his spare time, Chand began collecting materials from demolition sites around the city. He recycled these materials into his own vision of the divine kingdom of Sukrani, choosing a gorge in a forest near Sukhna Lake for his work. The gorge had been designated as a land conservancy, a forest buffer established in 1902 that nothing could be built on. Chand’s work was illegal, but he was able to hide it for 18 years before it was discovered by the authorities in 1975. By this time, it had grown into a 12-acre (49,000 m2) complex of interlinked courtyards, each filled with hundreds of pottery-covered concrete sculptures of dancers, musicians, and animals.\n
          His work was in danger of being demolished, but he was able to get public opinion on his side. In 1976 the park was inaugurated as a public space. Nek Chand was given a salary, a title ("Sub-Divisional Engineer, Rock Garden"), and 50 laborers so that he could concentrate full-time on his work. It appeared on an Indian stamp in 1983. The Rock Garden is still made out of recycled materials. With the government’s help, Chand was able to set up collection centers around the city for waste, especially rags and broken ceramics.\n
          When Chand left the country on a lecture tour in 1996, the city withdrew its funding, and vandals attacked the park. The Rock Garden Society took over the administration and upkeep of this unique visionary environment.\n
          The garden is visited by over 5,000 people daily, with more than 12 million visitors since its inception."</string>
      
       <string name="sukhnalake">"Sukhna Lake in Chandigarh, India is a reservoir at the foothills of the Himalayas, the Shivalik hills. This 3 km² rainfed lake was created in 1958 by damming the Sukhna Choe, a seasonal stream coming down from the Shivalik Hills. Originally the seasonal flow entered the lake directly causing heavy siltation. To check the inflow of silt, 25.42 km² of land was acquired in the catchment area and put under vegetation. In 1974, the Choe was diverted and made to bypass the lake completely, the lake being fed by three siltation pots, minimising the entry of silt into the lake itself.\n
           The lake was created by Le Corbusier and the Chief Engineer P L Verma. To preserve its tranquility Corbusier insisted that it be forbidden to motor boats and the top of the dam (promenade) prohibited to vehicular traffic. The lake is fringed by a golf course to the south, and Nek Chand's famous Rock Garden of Chandigarh to its west\n
           Sukhna is an inseparable part of the city of Chandigarh. Le Corbusier had foreseen that the residents of the city would be drawn it for the 'care of the body and spirit'. The city planners were deeply attached to the lake. So much so that Pierre Jeanneret's ashes were immersed in the lake in 1970 as per his wishes by his niece.\n
           The roof of the 'bandh' or dam has become a favorite promenade. Serious walkers pursue an exercise regime, families enjoy an evening stroll and nature lovers mingle with children on roller skates. Photographers and painters love to capture its scenic beauty of the setting sun, or the heavily clouded monsoon sky, or the early morning mist in winter set amidst the tranquility of the lake. Even anglers do not leave unrewarded.\n
           Sukhna has a membership-based Lake Club with lawns, a gym, indoor games, swimming pool and tennis courts with both synthetic and grass courts. Boating, rowing, sculling, sailing, kayaking and water skiing can be enjoyed throughout the year.\n
           The lake, which was the venue for the Asian Rowing Championships, has the longest channel for rowing and yachting events in Asia. It also has facilities for other water sports like water surfing, skiing and sculling.
           During summers, there are streams of men, women and children from all walks of life offering voluntary service to desilt the lake bed for about three months. This annual ritual has been a regular feature since long ago.\n
           Sukhna Lake is the venue for many festive celebrations too. The most popular is the Mango Festival held during the monsoons when scores of varieties of mangoes are on display. From time-to-time other food festivals, featuring specialities from different Indian States, are also held here, along with cultural performances."</string>

       <string name="punjabhaveli">"Haveli stands as a tribute to the glorious past and lifestyle of Punjab. The rich culture of Punjab is well depicted in the ambience and hospitality of Haveli.
Haveli is not just a restaurant; it is a holistic experience of Punjab which is derived from the various food stalls, cultural stores and the impeccable décor. There are elements like a life-size truck, a dummy well, colourful bangles, parandis etc. that add up to the ethnicity of the place. Guests can shop for souvenirs at the stores selling traditional artefacts.
Punjabi food is world-renown and we have taken the efforts to maintain that expectation by offering authentic flavours of Punjab. As the name suggests, Haveli offers every guest a grand meal served in a palatial way. The staff dressed in traditional Punjabi attire ensure that every guest has a pleasant experience to take back home.
Haveli as a place was conceptualised by Mr.Satish Jain. During his childhood he saw the vast and rich culture of Punjab where guests at home were treated as GOD. Creating Haveli is his effort to keep the Punjabi tradition alive. He did a lot of research which has helped him to look into the finer details of everything from exquisite décor to delicious food.
Haveli has frozen time to that golden era for generations to come and experience the splendour of Punjab in its true sense.\n
“Haveli” meaning a big palatia house with all the possible facilities available at that point of time and was commonly known as the rich mans house. This is the Punjabi Dhaba serving vegetarian Punjabi food. As the name suggests, Haveli offers every guest a grand meal served in a palatial way. The stewards as dressed in the typical."</string>

<string name="golkonda">"Golconda fort is a majestic monument, which lies on the western outskirts of Hyderabad city. It speaks of a great cultural heritage of 400 years and is regarded as a place worth visiting. Built by Mohammed Quli Qutub Shah in 1525, it stands as the epitome of Nawabi culture and grandeur. A Well Planned Architecture : The magnificent architecture of the Golconda fort is manifest in its acoustic system, the structural grandeur of the palaces and ingenious water supply system. The fort was famous for its diamond trade and the 'Kohinoor' diamond is said to have come from here. One is perplexed to see the meticulous details of the architecture and the fading gardens, which were once upon a time replete with sprawling lawns and playing fountains.

Golconda is built on a granite hill 120m high, and is surrounded by crenulated ramparts constructed of large masonry blocks weighing several tonnes. The design of the ventilation reveals the brilliant planning of the architects; they are designed to let in a flow of fresh cool breeze, which is a respite from the heat of summer.

The massive gates are studded with large pointed iron spikes to prevent elephants from battering them down. The outer wall surrounding the entire township of Golconda, is about 11-km long, and is strongly fortified. In its heyday, the 10-km long road from Golconda to outer Hyderabad was a fabulous market selling jewellery, diamonds, pearls and other gems, which were famous all over the world. 
One of the most remarkable features of Golconda is its system of acoustics- a hand clap at a certain point below the dome at the entrance reverberates and can be heard clearly at the 'Bala Hissar', the highest point almost a kilometre away, palaces, factories, water supply system and the famous 'Rahban' cannon, that was used during the last seize of Golconda by Aurangazeb, to whom the fort ultimately fell."</string>

<string name="hussainsagar">"Hussain Sagar is a lake in Hyderabad, India, built by Hazrat Hussain Shah Wali in 1562, during the rule of Ibrahim Quli Qutb Shah. It was a lake of 24 square kilom
Tank Bund
Tank bund road

Built in the 16th century the lake was named to express the gratitude of Ibrahim Quli Qutub Shah to Hussain Shah Wali who helped him to recover from illness. It is a sprawling artificial lake that holds water perennially, built during the reign of Ibrahim Qutub Shah, across a tributary of the river Musi in 1562. Linking the twin cities of Hyderabad and Secunderabad, the lake and its environs have several parks and scenic spots. The broad road on the tank bund is lined with lawns and 33 statues of famous personalities of the State stand along the bund of the lake. The well laid out Lumbini park located in the Buddha Purnima project has a musical fountain.

The lake is encompassed on one side by the beautiful Lumbini Park, an amusement park for the young and old alike. Then there is the enchanting Birla Mandir hewn on a hillock nearby. Standing on the Tank Bund at night, one is awe-struck to see the glimmering row of lights outlining the lake that look like “a diamond studded necklace”. This is the necklace road being readied to enhance the beauty of Hussain Sagar.

The majestic white arch that forms the entrance stands high and immaculate into the bluish white sky beckoning the motorists a free and easy passage on the wide long stretch of the Tank Bund. The two lions standing straight in support of the roof of the arch beside the pillars and the tapered dome with globular design akin to pinnacles on top are all styled after the traditional Hindu temple designs, much like the “simha dwaram” (the lion gateway). Its uniqueness lies in the fact that it connects the twin cities of Hyderabad and Secunderabad. Throughout the year the Tank Bund presents a picture of hustle-bustle of the regular traffic.
Statue of Buddha

An 18 meter high monolithic statue of Lord Buddha towers over the lake from atop the Rock of Gibraltar. The road on the Tank-Bund which originally was very narrow was widened in 1946 when Sir Mirza Ismail was the Prime Minister of Hyderabad. Further widening and beautification of the Tank-Bund took place during 1987-88 with the addition of fountains with dancing waters, tantalising coloured lighting during nights, and the installation of nearly thirty three (33) well sculptured bronze statues mounted on high platforms, in the memory of historical and eminent personalities of Andhra Pradesh. The idea of erecting a giant monolith Buddha statue in the midst of Hussainsagar lake on the Gibraltar rock was a part of the Buddha Poornima project in 1985. The monolithic statue was chiselled out of a white granite rock, weighting 450 tons. It was carved by 200 sculptors for two years. The statue was transported to Hyderabad in November 1988.After the initial problems, the statue was erected on 12 April 1992 on a red coloured Lotus pedestral. Attached to it, Lumbini park was inaugurated with musical fountains, Bonsai Plants and a boat ride from Lumbini Park to the Buddha Statue. The whole atmosphere reflects peace and persevence.

A project feasibility report has been prepared for the conservation and restoration of Hussain Sagar Lake under National Lake Conservation Plan. The Hussain Sagar Lake has been the centre of Hyderabad civilisation and is among the most beautiful national heritage. It has played a major role in the economy of the State of Andhra Pradesh through its attraction of tourists as well as its utilisation as a source of food and water.
Lake in the evening

During the past few years grave concern is being voiced by people from different walks of life over the deteriorating conditions of Hussain Sagar Lake. As a result of heavy anthropogenic pressures, the lake eco-systems are not only strengthening in its surface becoming poor in quality, posing health hazards to the people living in close proximity to the lake. Over the years the entire eco-system of Hussain Sagar Lake has changed. The water quality has deteriorated considerably during the last three decades. Over the years the lake has become shallow due to siltation and accumulation of plant debris. Many undesirable changes in the structure of biological communities have resulted and some important species have either declined or completely disappeared. Realising the importance of conservation of Hussain Sagar Lake, a project has been formulated. This project shall be implemented by APPCB, Hyderabad, India. In this respect, a project feasibility report has been prepared for the approval and financing from NLCP. The PFR focuses various physical, chemical, biological features of lakes including the technical and other sub-projects for the conservation of lake. Abstract of costs of all technical and other sub-projects have also been given in the PFR.

The Tank Bund dams Hussain Sagar Lake on the eastern side and connects the twin cities of Hyderabad and Secunderabad. There are 33 statues of famous people of Andhra Pradesh erected by former chief minister N.T. Rama Rao. The most popular promenade Tank Bund dams the Hussain Sagar large lake that connects the twin cities of Hyderabad and Secunderabad. In the middle of the lake is the "Rock of Gibraltar", on which stands the statue of Buddha. [2] This boulevard has beautiful gardens on both sides, with well laid foot paths and benches, and a good volume of traffic running in between. This road gets busy during the evenings as people come here to enjoy the view and cool air from the lake and to relax at gardens. Moving further from the Tank bund road towards the other side one can connect with the Necklace road, which is another popular boulevard which many consider as a twin to the Tank bund. The sailing club is present close to the Tank bund, where many sailors participate in events held at te lake throughout the year.

Parallel to the Tank bund, is the Lower Tank Bund road which was primarily built to reduce traffic congestion. This lower Tank Bund road is heralded by the well known Missamma temple, the sprawling green Indira Park, Hyderabad, Bharat Sevashram Sangha, Ramakrishna Mission and Snow world. An important flyover Telugu Talli flyover rises from the Lower tank bund road and flies across the end of the Tank bund road
    "</string>

<string name="veerabhadratemple">"The Veerabhadra temple is also known as Lepakshi temple. It is situated in Anantapur district of Andhra Pradesh. This temple is an ultimate testimony for Vishwakarma brothers, who sculpted these temples.

This temple is considered as one of the 108 Shiva Kshetras. 

This temple is dedicated to Hindu deity Veerabhadra. 

It is believed that Veerabhadra relieves the person of his sins and grants them wisdom.

According to Hindu mythology, Sati was the consort of Shiva and self-immolated in yajna fire. After that Shiva got infuriated and gave rise to Veerabhadra. 

 Veerabhadra is depicted as a warrior who eventually blinded God Bhaga (God of wealth) and fought with many other countless gods. They fled the battlefield unable to sustain his power.

There are many temples dedicated to Veerabhadra. They are situated in the town of Veerbhadra , near Rishikesh in Uttrakhand and Pasumbalur, near the Perabalur district in Tamilnadu.
The temple's plan is irregular. Its three main parts are as follows:

Virabhadra shrine with its ardhamandapa

Mukha-mandapa

kalyanamandapa. 

All the three glimmer with painting and sculpture. 

Most of these sculptures portray the mythological puranic episodes like 'Ananthasayana', 'Dattatreya ', 'Chaturmukha Brahma ', 'Tumburu', 'Narada ' and 'Rambha'.

In the central part of the temple, where the Virabhadra shrine stands, there are eight shrines in all. Each shrine has sixteen massive pillars depicting life-size sculptors of deities. On the ceiling, there is a huge and celebrated painting of Lord Veerabhadra. 

The mukhamandapa (Main Hall) has oblong structure 24 m by 7 m that is supported by seventy brilliantly sculptured columns. There are sixty more columns in the outer rows. Two of them are virtually hanging pillars. On the roof of the main hall, there are eight rectangular painted panels. One that is longest is about 18 m in length and only 2m in breadth. Here, the story of King Manu nidhi Chola is painted. Three large slabs in the second prakara carry striking sculpture. One of them is of the Ganesha . This image is 2.3 m high, and it stands on a 1.40 m high platform. Near to it there is a huge Shivalinga under a seven hooded cobra. The height of this Cobra is 5.5 m high. One can find the crack in the center of the base. According to the local legend, one of the sculptors made this during his lunch hours. During that time, the sculpture's mother brought him his meal. She saw the sculpture of her child, she was surprised. She praised the beauty of the sculpture. Immediately there is the spilt in the base of the sculpture. A mother’s praise of her son's sculptures was considered inauspicious.

In the kalyanamandapa, there are thirty-eight columns that excellently depict divine figures. These columns India’s second largest sculpture of Nandi (the bull) nearly about 6 ft. Height and 8 mts. placed about 200m, north east of the Veerabhadra temple. The majestic artistry of Nandi sculpture is mesmerizing for the tourists.  

The temple is a storehouse of painting and sculpture. Its murals claim an honored place in the annals of Hindu aesthetics.

One of the most famous paintings from temple's splendid paintings is the colossal painting of Virabhadra in the central hall. In the 'Hall of Dance', one can trace eight panels, depicting Puranic legends on the ceiling. Most of the paintings and murals have been devastated by the ravages of times. 

It can be concluded that Veerabhadra temple is a notable store of expertise work, which is on the verge of extinction. This temple has the blend awesome architecture, mythological tales, paintings and sculptures and thus certainly deserves a visit.

The saga associated with the Veerabhadra temple:

One day Virupanna went to the Kurma saila hill. This hill is also known as the hill of the tortoise as it resembles a resting tortoise. There he happened to see a small temple of Papanasa.He decided to construct a temple complex there.

Virupanna was working as the treasurer of the province of Penukonda, thus, had the finance at his disposal for building the temple.
 
He engaged many architects, sculptors and painters. To start with, he had a huge prakara wall built to enclose the Papanasa shrine and many others in its proximity. He had many mandapas that also erected within. But, meanwhile, envious persons told the emperor that the treasurer had misappropriated the money. 

He asked Virupanna to present in the court. In the anticipation of the punishment, he plucked out his eyes and smashed them upon a wall in the temple. There are red spots on the wall as the remnant of this incident. During rains, the red spots begin watering, and people believe that Virupanna is weeping. The blinded Virupanna used to roam about the temple. He felt bad that he had to leave the temple, of course, left unfinished. He wailed his hard fate that he could not able to see the glory of the Almighty.

According to historical facts, Virupanna had built the Kalyana Venkatasavara temple in NaryanVanam and made gifts to the Tirumala and Sri Kalahasti temples.

He was promoted from an original post to high office in Penukonda and Chandra giri provinces. Though people exaggerated about him in their folklores, but the fact remains the same that he had built the Veerabhadra temple. 
    "</string>

<string name="tirumalavenkateswaratemple">"Tirumala Venkateswara Temple is a famous Hindu temple located in the hill town Tirumala, near Tirupati in the Chittoor district of Andhra Pradesh, India. Tirumala, is a hill town in Chittoor district in the state of Andhra Pradesh, India. Tirumala is a Firstmost divine piligrim center of Hindu / Vedha Religion, popularly known as Sri Venkateswara Temple - which is dedicated for the Supreme God Shri mann Narayana / Maha Vishnu. As like Rama Avathara / Krishna Avathara are known as Vibhava avathara of the God, the Sri Rengam/Tirumala/Badrinath are the existing places of Archavatharas of the Supreme God.\n
Vishnu in the form of Lord Venkateshwara at Tirumala Venkateshwara (Sanskrit and Telugu), also known as Venkatachalapathy or Srinivasa or Balaji, is the supreme God believed to be a form of the Hindu Deity Lord Vishnu. He appeared in this Yuga Kali Yuga for saving the people who have fallen deeply and are deluded in three modes of material nature. 

Lord Venkateshwara means supreme God who destroys the sins of the people in this material world 'ven+kata+eshwara=sins+destroyer+supremegod'). He is Vishnu, who is transcendental to the material energy, Vishnu does not have direct contact with material people, and therefore yogis carry out severe penances to have a vision of Vishnu's lotus feet. How ever, in the kali yuga people have fallen to the point that they have even lost themselves due to ignorance in bodily consciousness. Lord Vishnu out of love towards his devotees therefore incarnated as Venkateshwara.

The exact period in which the temple was founded is not known, and tradition has it that the temple is Swayambhustala, meaning that it came into existence on its own without anyone constructing it. According to folk legends, there was a huge anthill at Tirupati. A farmer heard a voice from the heavens asking him to feed the ants. By chance the local king heard the voice and began supplying milk for the ants himself. His compassion resulted in the liquid uncovering a magnificent idol of Lord Venkateshwara hidden beneath the anthill. 

According to some evidence the history of the temple dates back almost 2,000 years. In ancient times, a queen called Samavai, belonging to the Pallava dynasty (614 AD), is said to have consecrated the first silver image here. The temple is also mentioned in Sangam poetry (500 BC - 2000 AD).

Numerous temple inscriptions from the 9th century record details of the temple and contributions made by both Pallavas and Chola Kings. It is believed that originally there was only one shrine at Tirumala. When the Vaishnavite saint, Ramanuja, visited Andhra in the 12th century, the temple at Tirupathi was built. The Chola period saw the temple complex prosper and expand further. In 1517, Krishnadevaraya, on one of his many visits to the temple, donated gold and jewels enabling the Vimana (inner shrine) roofing to be gilded.
    "</string>
    
<string name="visakhamuseum">"Visakha Museum (Full name: Visakhapatnam Municipal Corporation Museum) is a museum located in the port city of Visakhapatnam in Andhra Pradesh, India which houses the historical treasures and artifacts of the Kalingandhra region.[1] Collections available for viewing in the museum include ancient armory, crockery, coins, silk costumes, jewelry, stuffed animals, portraits, manuscripts, letters, diaries, scrapbooks, periodicals, and maps. All of these were used by the early settlers in the region. There are many models of warships, planes and submarines. There are many historical items presented by different countries too. There we also have a search light reflector 30", route of Vasco-da-Gamas maiden voyage to India and then comes the thought said by nehru-"TO BE SECURE ON LAND;WE MUST BE SUPREME AT SEA".

Visakhapatnam has volumes of history to talk about. But the credit of preserving records about the Visakhapatnams past goes to the Visakha Museum, also called Corporation Museum. The Visakha Museum is located at an old Dutch Bungalow on the RK Beach Road.

The Museum has some of the best and finest artistic items put on display. Portraits, some of them even at life-size depicting the members of the Royal family of the Vizianagaram and Bobbili, Two Armour suits, two stands of spears and muzzleloading guns, several ancient weapons such as steel bows, handguns that date back to the British-rule times are some of the things one should not miss.

The Visakha Museum also showcases some of the artifacts collected from other institutions. These include the 250-lb bomb that was dropped by the Japanese during the World War II. The shell bomb did not however explode. The shell bomb is now put on display at the Museum.

The Museum preserves the coconut that was broken by the then Prime Minister Pt. Jawaharlal Nehru when he came for the inauguration of the first ship that was indigenously built ? the S.S Jala Usha.

The Bronze busts used by the first Indian Chairman of Visakhapatnam Port Trust Nanjundiah were also preserved.

Father of the Nation ? Gandhiji has lots of connections with Visakhapatnam. The Museum has a nice collection of photographs of Gandhiji ? particularly the ones during his visit to Vizag when he stayed at the Nkitam House. The desk used by him during his visit was also preserved. The desk was later used by Tenneti Vishwanatham.
The Museum is currently headed by Curator Prof. E.V. Gangadharam who was also the Director, Centre for Marine Archaeology. Mr. S. Prabhu Das is the Superintendent-in-charge, Museum."</string>

<string name="kanakadurgatemple">"The temple of Kanaka Durga the Goddess of power, riches and benevolence and the presiding deity of Vijayawada, is swarmed by lakhs of pilgrims for worship during the Navarathri festival which is celebrated with Religious fervour, pomp and festivity. The small but ancient temple of Kanaka Durga , a top the Indrakeeladri hill on the banks of the Sacred river Krishna in Vijayawada abounds with legends of historical interest.
Indrakeeladri is unique in that it has been the chosen abode of Kanaka Durga and Her consort Malleswara as Swayambhu (the self-existent one). Here Durga is one the right side of Malleswara as against the tradition of Goddesses taking their position on the left of their consorts. This shows that Shakthi is predominant on the Indrakeeladri.
Legend has it that the demons acquired great powers by appeasing the Gods and began harassing the sages on the earth. Goddess Parvathi assumed various forms to kill these demons. It was kausiki to kill Sumbhu and Nisambhu, Mahisasura Mardini to kill Mahishasura and Durga to kill Durgamasura. "Kanaka Durga because she was aglow with golden hues, and prayed Her to stay on earth and bless them. Kanaka Durga asked Keeludu an ardent devotee to take the form of hill to enable Her stay on him. Thus Keeladri became the abode of Durga. She took the form of Mahisasura Mardini with eight arms holding different weapons, riding on a lion and trampling Mahishasura on the hill of Indrakeeladri. Her consort Shiva took his place on an adjacent hillrock as Jyothirlinga. He was worshipped by Lord Brahma with jasmines (Mallelu) whereby he got the name of Malleswara Swamy. As celestial beings like Indra visited the place, the hill came to be called Indrakeeladri.
Here it was according to another legend, that Arjuna performed penance and fought with Lord Shiva, who had appeared in the guise of Kiratha to win pasupathastra, the most powerful weapon. So this place is also called phalguna theertha.
When Indrakeeladri came in the way of the River Krishna the Gods requested the hill to allow the river to pass through it to join the sea. Keeludu obliged and gave a small passage for the river. But the ferocious Krishna made the passage larger than permitted and carried a part of the hill four miles downstream to Yanamalakuduru, where there is now a hillrock called "Thelukonda" or floating hillrock. According to another legend, Kanaka Durga borrowed the nose-stud of the Krishna and to avoid returning it jumped up the hill. Krishna vowed to take back her ornament by raising her level to the hill top by the end of kaliyuga
Adi-Sankaracharya visited the temple and installed the Srichakra and initiated workship of Kanaka Durga in vedic ways.
Hiuan Tsang, a Chinese traveler wrote that he has seen many stone inscriptions in the vicinity of the temple that revealed historic events.
Palakethu Bhupaludu made two inscriptions in the period 1150-1240 A.D. One related to unimpeaching Madhava Varma the ruler of this area. The son of poor women was killed when he fell under the wheels of the chariot of the kings son.
When she sought justice, Madhava Varmas advisers said that he should be punished with death. But they felt that the offender being the son of the king, could be spared the punishment. When Madhava Varma shown his impartiality by punishing his son with death, there rained gold on Vijayawada and both the boys were blessed to live again.
In yet another incident Malleswara stood by one of his staunch devotees Sripathi Pandithaiah, who believed there was no other God by Malleswara; and his stubbornness made the people ostracize him and he was even refused fire. The enraged Pandithaiah sought the blessings of Malleswara and cursed the people that they would not get fire any more, for he had taken possession of it, packed it in a silk cloth and hung it on a branch of a Sami Vriksham. The people had to apologise to Pandithaiah at the instance of their King, to get back the fire.
The nine-day festival of Navarathri ends on Vijaya Dasami Day when people worship arms and perform ayudha Pooja. Local chieftains used to celebrate the festival with pomp. Once a police officer refused them permission to display their arms on Vijaya Dasami day. He got a cable from that he was dismissed from service following many complaints against him. Terrified by the events, the Officer not only permitted the people to celebrate Vijaya Dasami but also took part in it. Later he got another cable canceling his dismissal order. Thenceforth, it became a tradition for policemen to celebrate Vijaya Dasami, which is still in vogue.
Kanaka Durga is specially decorated as Balatripura Sundari, Gayathri Annapoorna. Mahalakshmi, Saraswathi, Lalitha Tripura Sundari, Durga Devi, Mahissura Mardini and Raja Rajeswari Devi on each day of the Narvarathri festival. On Vijaya Dasami day, the deities are taken in a swan-shaped boat around the Krishna river, popularity known as "Theppotsavam".
Though a ghat road was laid in 1969, most of the pilgrims prefer to climb the steps leading to the temple an arduons task for women and children. Some devotees climb the hill, decorating the steps with turmeric powder and vermilion to redeem their pledge of Metla Pooja."</string>

 <string name="redfort">"The Red Fort was the residence of the Mughal emperor of India for nearly 200 years, until 1857. It is located in the centre of Delhi and houses a number of museums. In addition to accommodating the emperors and their households, it was the ceremonial and political centre of Mughal government and the setting for events critically impacting the region.

Constructed in 1648 by the fifth Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan as the palace of his fortified capital Shahjahanabad,[2] the Red Fort is named for its massive enclosing walls of red sandstone and is adjacent to the older Salimgarh Fort, built by Islam Shah Suri in 1546. The imperial apartments consist of a row of pavilions, connected by a water channel known as the Stream of Paradise (Nahr-i-Behisht). The fort complex is considered to represent the zenith of Mughal creativity under Shah Jahan and although the palace was planned according to Islamic prototypes, each pavilion contains architectural elements typical of Mughal buildings that reflect a fusion of Timurid, Persian and Hindu traditions. The Red Fort’s innovative architectural style, including its garden design, influenced later buildings and gardens in Delhi, Rajasthan, Punjab, Kashmir, Braj, Rohilkhand and elsewhere.[1] With the Salimgarh Fort, it was designated a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2007 as part of the Red Fort Complex.[1][3]

On Independence Day (15 August), the Prime Minister of India hoists the national flag at the main gate of the fort and delivers a nationally-broadcast speech from its ramparts."</string>

  <string name="humayuntomb">"The last refuge of Mughal Emperor Humayun reminds rather of a luxurious palace, than a tomb.

Located in the eastern part of Dehli, Humayun’s tomb is one of the best preserved Mughal monuments.  This spellbinding mausoleum is the first example of Mughal architecture in India.

After a century from its construction Humayun’s tomb inspired the construction of the more famous Taj Mahal.
From the point of view of the history of architecture this building is the unique connecting link between the Gur Emir, where Humayun’s ancestor Tamerlane is buried, and the mausoleum of his grandson Shah Jahan, i.e. Taj Mahal.

Humayun’s tomb was built thanks to the initiative of his widow Hamida Banu Begum, who commenced the construction of a mausoleum for her deceased husband in 1565, nine years after his death. The construction was finished in 1572. 

The architecture of the tomb is strongly influenced by Persian architecture. The architect of the building Mirak Mirza Ghiyas himself was of Persian origin. Ghiyas constructed the tomb in the center of a Persian-style chaharbagh garden (translated from Farsi - four gardens) with quadrilateral form. The garden, divided in four main parts by walkways or flowing water is created to resemble the paradise garden described in the Quran. These four main parts on their turn are separated by channels to 36 parts.

From the 17th to the 19th centuries the garden was gradually filled with the tombs of Humayun’s descendants and his entourage. Several Mughal emperors are even buried inside Humayun’s mausoleum. Humayun’s mausoleum has earned the title of necropolis of the Mughal dynasty. No sepulcher in India or elsewhere contains such a high number of tombs of the Mughal emperors and their relatives. Moreover, Humayun’s tomb is the first garden-tomb on the Indian subcontinent. 

The mausoleum stands on a massive platform which has a height of up to 7 meters. The building is constructed from red sandstone, while the tomb itself is made of yellow and black marble. The two-storied mausoleum is crowned with white Persian style marble dome that seems weightless and imponderable. The height of Humayun's Tomb is 47 meters, and its breadth is 91 meters.

      "</string>
  
   <string name="lotustemple">"The Lotus Temple, located in New Delhi, India, is a Bahá'í House of Worship completed in 1986. Notable for its flowerlike shape, it serves as the Mother Temple of the Indian subcontinent and has become a prominent attraction in the city. The Lotus Temple has won numerous architectural awards and been featured in hundreds of newspaper and magazine articles
All Bahá'í Houses of Worship, including the Lotus Temple, share certain architectural elements, some of which are specified by Bahá'í scripture. `Abdu'l-Bahá, the son of the founder of the religion, stipulated that an essential architectural character of a House of Worship is a nine-sided circular shape. While all current Bahá'í Houses of Worship have a dome, this is not regarded as an essential part of their architecture. Bahá'í scripture also states that no pictures, statues or images be displayed within the House of Worship and no pulpits or altars be incorporated as an architectural feature (readers may stand behind simple portable lecture stands).
Model of the temple at the information centre
Inspired by the lotus flower, the design for the House of Worship in New Delhi is composed of 27 free-standing marble-clad "petals" arranged in clusters of three to form nine sides. The nine doors of the Lotus Temple open onto a central hall slightly more than 40 meters tall that is capable of holding up to 2,500 people. The surface of the House of Worship is made of white marble from Penteli mountain in Greece, the very same from which many ancient monuments and other Bahá'í Houses of Worship are built. Along with its nine surrounding ponds and the gardens, the Lotus Temple property comprises 26 acres (105,000 m²; 10.5 ha).

The site is in the village of Bahapur, in the National Capital Territory of Delhi. The architect was an Iranian, who now lives in Canada, named Fariborz Sahba. He was approached in 1976 to design it and later oversaw its construction. The structural design was undertaken by the UK firm Flint and Neill. The major part of the funds needed to buy this land was donated by Ardishír Rustampúr of Hyderabad, Sindh, who gave his entire life savings for this purpose in 1953. The construction company was ECC Construction Group of Larsen and Toubro Limited. A portion of construction budget was saved and used to build a greenhouse to study indigenous plants and flowers that would be appropriate for use on the site."</string>
       
 <string name="rashtrapatibhavan">"The splendour of the Rashtrapati Bhavan is multi-dimensional. It is a vast mansion and its architecture is breathtaking. More than these, it has a hallowed existence in the annals of democracy for being the residence of the President of the largest democracy in the world. Few official residential premises of the Head of the State in the world will match the Rashtrapati Bhavan in terms of its size, vastness and its magnificence.
The present day Rashtrapati Bhavan was the erstwhile residence of the British Viceroy. Its architect was Edwin Landseer Lutyens. The decision to build a residence in New Delhi for the British Viceroy was taken after it was decided in the Delhi Durbar of 1911 that the capital of India would be shifted from Calcutta to Delhi in the same year. It was constructed to affirm the permanence of British rule in India. This building gave the impression, in the words of a critique, the setting of a perpetual Durbar. The building and its surroundings were supposed to be 'an empire in stone', 'exercising imperial sway' and containing in it, "the abode of a disinterested elite whose rule was imposed from above". That 'empire in stone' and the perpetual Durbar was transformed to be the permanent institution of democracy on 26th January 1950 when Dr. Rajendra Prasad became the first President of India and occupied this building to preserve, protect and defend the Constitution of India. It was from that day that this building was renamed as Rashtrapati Bhavan - the President's House.
Apart from Edwin Lutyens, the Chief architect and Chief Engineer Hugh Keeling there were many Indian contractors who were involved in the construction of this building.
The sanctioned amount for the building was earmarked at 400,000 pounds. However the long span of seventeen years required for the construction of the building raised its cost to 877,136 pounds (then Rs. 12.8 million). The actual amount incurred in not only the construction of the building but also the Mughal Garden and the staff quarters amounted to Rs. 14 million. Edwin Lutyens was reported to have remarked that the money invested in the construction of the building was smaller in amount as compared to the cost of two warships.
It is interesting to note that the building which was scheduled to be completed in four years took seventeen years and on the eighteenth year of its completion India became independent.
This vast mansion has got four floors and 340 rooms. With a floor area of 200, 000 square feet it is built by using 700 million bricks and three million cubic feet of stone. Hardly any steel has gone into the construction of the building.
The most prominent and distinguishing aspect of Rashtrapati Bhavan is its dome which is superimposed on its structure. It is visible from a distance and the most eye-catching round roof with a circular base in the heart of Delhi. While Lutyens ostensibly acknowledged the design of the dome to the pantheon of the Rome, it is very strongly believed by informed analysts that the dome was structured in the pattern of the great Stupa at Sanchi. The pre-dominance of Indian architecture in the dome is evident from the fact that it is encircled by railings of Sanchi origin. In fact the whole of Rashtrapati Bhavan embodies in it Indian architectural patterns such as Buddhist railings, chhajjas, chhatris and jaalis."</string>
 
  <string name="qutabminar">"Qutub Minar in Delhi is world heritage site. The tall minaret was constructed in 1192 by Qutab-ud-din Aibak, and later completed by his successor Iltutmish. The soaring conical tower is an exquisite example of Indo-Islamic Afghan architecture.
Qutub Minar Height : 72.5 meteres or 237.8 feet
Steps in minar : 379 steps
Year Built : 1192
Address : Aurobindo Marg, Mehrauli, New Delhi
Built by :Qutab-ud-din Aibak
There are evidence that Qutubminar was built much before by Hindu emperors. Later Kuttubuddin has replaced the writing on stones.
Qutub Minar is a World Heritage Site and has survived the ravages of time impressively. The Minar of Delhi is surrounded by a lush green garden, which is an ideal leisurely place for visitors. Qutab Minar is the favourite destination of tourists. It is India's most visited monument attracting around 3.9 million visitors every year.

Each of the 5 storeys and tower of Qutub Minar has unique designs.
It was hit by lightening couple of times and was damaged. The subsequent rulers repaired it. Thus it is standing mightily as it was before till date.
Qutab Minar is a great masterpiece of Mughal architecture. The base of the Qutub Minar measures 14.32 meters and the top of the structure measures 2.75 meters. The bird eye's view of Delhi city from the top is amazing. The base of first storey has alternate angular and circular flutings, the second one is round. The third storey of the Qutub Minar has angular flutings. The balconies projecting out heighten the beauty of the Minar.
The tower is so high that around 379 steps are needed to be climbed to reach the top. Another taller tower adjacent to Qutub Minar is named Alai Minar which is somewhat tilted in one direction.
The verses from the holy Qur'an are carved on sandstone walls of Qutub Minar. This monument serves the purpose of calling people for prayer in the Quwwat-ul-Islam mosque. This is a tower of victory, a monument that signify the might of Islam, or a tower for keeping a check for defense.
There are claims and evidence that Qutubminar was built much before by Hindu emperors. Later Kuttubuddin has replaced the writing on stones. The stones has hindu God pictures on one side and arabic writing on other side. 
Stones dislodged from the Minar have Hindu images on one side with Arabic lettering on the other. Those stones are now in Museum. These stone represent that invaders used to remove the stone- dressing of Hindu buildings, turn the stones inside out to hide the image facial and inscribe Arabic lettering on the new frontage."</string>
  
 <string name="indiagate">"The India Gate, (originally called the All India War Memorial), is a war memorial located astride the Rajpath, on the eastern edge of the ‘ceremonial axis’ of New Delhi, formerly called Kingsway. India gate is a memorial to 82,000 soldiers of the undivided British Indian Army who died in the period 1914–21 in the First World War, in France, Flanders, Mesopotamia, Persia, East Africa, Gallipoli and elsewhere in the Near and the Far East, and the Third Anglo-Afghan War. 13,300 servicemen's names, including some soldiers and officers from the United Kingdom, are inscribed on the gate.[1][2] The India Gate, even though a war memorial, evokes the architectural style of the triumphal arch like the Arch of Constantine, outside the Colosseum in Rome, and is often compared to the Arc de Triomphe in Paris, and the Gateway of India in Mumbai. It was designed by Sir Edwin Lutyens.[1]

In 1971, following the Bangladesh Liberation war, a small simple structure, consisting of a black marble plinth, with reversed rifle, capped by war helmet, bounded by four eternal flames, was built beneath the soaring Memorial Archway. This structure, called Amar Jawan Jyoti, or the Flame of the Immortal Soldier, since 1971 has served as India’s Tomb of the Unknown Soldier.
The India Gate situated in India delhi, was part of the work of the Imperial War Graves Commission (IWGC), which came into existence in December 1917 for building war graves and memorials to soldiers killed in the First World War [3] The foundation stone of the All-India War Memorial was laid on 10 February 1921, at 4:30 PM, by the visiting Duke of Connaught in a solemn soldierly ceremony attended by Officers and Men of the Indian Army, Imperial Service Troops, the Commander in Chief, and Chelmsford, the Victory.[4] On the occasion, the viceroy said, "The stirring tales of individual heroism, will live for ever in the annals of this country", and that the memorial which was a tribute to the memory of heroes, "known and unknown” would inspire, future generations to endure hardships with similar fortitude and "no less valour"."</string>

<string name="sheeshmahal">"The palace of the Nawab of Farrukhnagar aligns the main bazaar of the town as do many other heritage structures in the town. Built by Faujdar Khan in 1711 CE, it is a double-storey structure in red sandstone, Mughal bricks and Jhajjar stone, used commonly in the buildings of the period in the district. It has decorative interiors of elaborate mirror inlay work, hence its name, Sheesh Mahal (Glass Palace). Its baradari, literally a pavilion with 12 doorways, now houses Municipal committee office, once housed a school.[citation needed] The palace opens on to a large courtyard with water channel in the centre, it was fed by a nearby baoli or stepwell, it is also believed that in olden days, the queen used to visit the baoli for taking bath from Sheesh Mahal through a tunnel, which has since been closed. The palace is being restored by the archaeological department and its premises also has a memorial dedicated to the martyrs of Indian Rebellion of 1857 from the town."</string>

<string name="kalpanachawlaplanetarium">"Kalpana Chawla Memorial Planetarium has been setup at Kurukshetra-Pehowa road (near Jyotisar Tirth) by Haryana State Council for Science and Technology, Govt. of Haryana in joint collaboration with National Council for Science Museums, Ministry of Culture, Govt. of India in memory of India's first woman Astronaut Dr. Kalpana Chawla. The planetarium built at a cost of 6.50 crores covers an area of 5 acres of land. Surrounded by sprawling green fields and lush Astro-park the planetarium is ideal for those who seek to escape from the din and dust, hustle and bustle of big cities. The planetarium offers a blend of peaceful surroundings and astronomy shows run using latest technology equipments. In a very short span of time the planetarium has emerged as one of unique and most favorite tourist spot of the city.
The excellent programmes and supporting exhibits placed inside and in the Astro-park help the students in particular and people at large in learning this frontier area of science and satisfy their curiosities with a whole range of information about the Space. The astronomy shows are usually run in Hindi language and special shows both in Hindi and English languages are also conducted on demand for groups."</string>

<string name="srikrishnamuseum">"In a bid to celebrate the Sri Krishna motif in this holy town, especially in the absence of any major historic structure, the Kurukshetra Development Board has set up the Sri Krishna Museum. This is the only centre of its kind in the entire country and its presence in Kurukshetra has special significance. 

The Artifacts On Display
The exhibits here display varied phases of Lord Krishna's life. Patta Chitra, Kangra, Madhubani and Pichhawai paintings, bronze collection dating to the times of the Pallava, Chola and Nayaka period celebrate the life of Sri Krishna. 

The wooden carvings showing 'Venugopala' and 'Dasavataras' of the Lord are excellent specimens of workmanship. The museum even has Sri Krishna as 'Venugopal' in ivory. Other images of Lord Krishna's colourful life include Krishna as a mischievous child, Krishna on the lotus leaf as the rain falls and Krishna vanquishing the lady demon "Putna". 'Kansa' being killed, Krishna holding aloft of the mountain on his little finger, his mirthful dance 'Ras' with Gopis and his role as a charioteer in the battle of Mahabharata are all depicted in the museum. "</string>

<string name="brahmasarovar">"Brahma Sarovar is an ancient water tank sacred to Hinduism in Thanesar, in the state of Haryana in North India.[1] Hinduism lays emphasis on taking bath for internal and external purity. Most religious sites have water tanks or sarovar in or near the temple/gurdwara
According to stories of myths, Lord Brahma created the universe from the land of Kurukshetra after a huge yajna. The Brahma Sarovar here is believed to be the cradle of civilization. The sarovar is also mentioned in the eleventh century AD memoirs of Al Beruni, called ‘Kitab-ul-Hind’.

A sacred shrine dedicated to Lord Shiva stands within the sarovar, accessible by a small bridge. According to scriptures, bathing in this sarovar increases the sanctity of performing the ‘ashvamedh yajna’. The tank offers a breath-taking sight during the Gita Jayanti celebrations held in the last week of November and early December every year when there will be ‘deep daan’ and ‘aarti’. This also happens to be the time when migratory birds from distant places wing it to the sarovar. The Birla Gita Mandir and Baba Nath’s haveli and temple are the neighbouring attractions."</string>

<string name="kingdomofdreams">"Kingdom of Dreams is India's first live entertainment, theatre and leisure destination.[1] It is located in Sector 29, Gurgaon in NCR Delhi, near the Leisure Valley Park. It was inaugurated on 29 January 2010 by the Chief Minister of Haryana[1] and opened to public on 18 September 2010 by Union Minister of Tourism, Kumari Selja. The opening showcased a special preview of the Bollywood musical, Zangoora, starring Hussain Kuwajerwala, Gauhar Khan and Kashmira Irani.[2] Spread over 6 acres (24,000 m2) and built at a cost of over Rs. 2 billion, Kingdom of Dreams is run by the Great Indian Nautanki Company (GINC), a joint venture between Apra Group and Wizcraft.

The destination consists of two theatres, Nautanki Mahal and the Showshaa Theatre, and a cultural and cuisine area known as Culture Gully.[3][4]

Bollywood actor Shah Rukh Khan was named the global ambassador of Kingdom of Dreams on 19 September 2010.[5][6] The 2010 Commonwealth Games' official theme song, Jiyo Utho Bado Jeeto by composer A R Rahman was launched in the complex on 28 August 2010, with a performance by Rahman, accompanied by dance performances by Hussain Kuwajerwala, Gauhar Khan and Kashmira Irani, on the theme of Zangoora - The Gypsy Prince."</string>

<string name="allenforestzoo">"Allen Forest Zoo(also called the Kanpur Zoo) is a 77-hectare (190-acre) zoo in Kanpur, the industrial hub of Uttar Pradesh in North India. It is the largest open green space in Kanpur. Originally a natural habitat for fauna, it is one of the few zoos in India created in a natural forest.
The Allen Forest Zoo is located about two kilometers (1.24 miles) from the city’s center.[2] In earlier colonial records, it is mentioned as being close to Nawabganj, a locality in kanpur. The zoo is an oasis of green, featuring a natural lake and ancient trees, and encompasses the largest land area of any zoological garden in Asia.

The zoo is open for visitors on all days from 9 AM to 4:30 PM, except on Mondays. Given its vast size, private four-wheeler vehicles are also allowed inside of the zoo for extra charge. Plastic bags are strictly banned inside of the zoo, and water is provided in coolers instead of in plastic bottles.

Mammals at the zoo include White Asian tigers, cheetah, leopard, jaguar, hyena, black bear, grizzly bear, sloth, rhinoceros, hippopotamus, monkeys, langur, baboons, Musk deer, deer, and antelope.[2] Chimpanzees (including a 26-year-old named Chhajju) and orangutans (including a 30-year-old named Mangal) have their own island. Some monkeys and deer are allowed to roam outside the enclosures as natural inhabitants of the zoo.

Amphibians at the zoo include Indian gharial.

The lion at the zoo died of an unknown disease during November of 2010. It is currently under consideration whether a current animal will be exchanged for a lion from a different zoo."</string>

<string name="tajmahal">"The Taj Mahal of Agra is one of the Seven Wonders of the World, for reasons more than just looking magnificent. It's the history of Taj Mahal that adds a soul to its magnificence: a soul that is filled with love, loss, remorse, and love again. Because if it was not for love, the world would have been robbed of a fine example upon which people base their relationships. An example of how deeply a man loved his wife, that even after she remained but a memory, he made sure that this memory would never fade away. This man was the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan, who was head-over-heels in love with Mumtaz Mahal, his dear wife. She was a Muslim Persian princess (her name Arjumand Banu Begum before marriage) and he was the son of the Mughal Emperor Jehangir and grandson of Akbar the Great. It was at the age of 14 that he met Mumtaz and fell in love with her. Five years later in the year 1612, they got married.

Mumtaz Mahal, an inseparable companion of Shah Jahan, died in 1631, while giving birth to their 14th child. It was in the memory of his beloved wife that Shah Jahan built a magnificent monument as a tribute to her, which we today know as the "Taj Mahal". The construction of Taj Mahal started in the year 1631. Masons, stonecutters, inlayers, carvers, painters, calligraphers, dome-builders and other artisans were requisitioned from the whole of the empire and also from Central Asia and Iran, and it took approximately 22 years to build what we see today. An epitome of love, it made use of the services of 22,000 laborers and 1,000 elephants. The monument was built entirely out of white marble, which was brought in from all over India and central Asia. After an expenditure of approximately 32 million rupees, Taj Mahal was finally completed in the year 1653.

It was soon after the completion of Taj Mahal that Shah Jahan was deposed by his own son Aurangzeb and was put under house arrest at nearby Agra Fort. Shah Jahan, himself also, lies entombed in this mausoleum along with his wife. Moving further down the history, it was at the end of the 19th century that British Viceroy Lord Curzon ordered a sweeping restoration project, which was completed in 1908, as a measure to restore what was lost during the Indian rebellion of 1857: Taj being blemished by British soldiers and government officials who also deprived the monument of its immaculate beauty by chiseling out precious stones and lapis lazuli from its walls. Also, the British style lawns that we see today adding on to the beauty of Taj were remodeled around the same time. Despite prevailing controversies, past and present threats from Indo-Pak war and environmental pollution, this epitome of love continuous to shine and attract people from all over the world."</string>

<string name="jamamasjid">"Jama Masjid in Agra is opposite the Agra fort and overlooking the Agra Fort Railway Station. The Jama Masjid is also popularly known as the Jami Masjid or "Friday Mosque". It is one of the larger mosques in India.
The Mosque was built by Mughal emperor, Shahjahan in 1648 and dedicated to his favourite daughter, Jahanara Begum. There was a spacious, octagonal Tripolia Chowk which existed between the Jama Masjid and the Delhi gate of the Agra Fort. This Tropolia was destroyed in order to create the Agra Fort Railway Station. The cloisters have engrailed arches supported on pillars. The main entrance is through the eastern side. The prayer chamber has a façade with a broad arched iwan in its centre and is adorned with slender turrets alternated with kiosks. Its dome is the largest and highest of the three domes crowning the sanctuary.

All the bulbous domes have inverted lotus and kalash finials on the top and have narrow zigzag courses of white marble alternated by broad bands of red stone. There is a fountain with four kiosks in its corners in the centre of the courtyard. The interiors of the western wall have a beautiful mihrab and pulpit in white marble. The Persian inscription in white marble inlaid with black stone on the archway of the central portal is in praise of Jahanara and Shah Jehan. The pristine beauty of the mosque must have been awesome as indicated by its comparison with Baitul-Mamur, the fabulous mosque of rubies and pearls situated in the fourth sky. It is said that once surrounded by a market place called Tripolia set in an octagonal (Muthamman) Chowk that was built between the Delhi Gate and the Jami Masjid. But, it was later destroyed in 1871-73 to acquire space for laying down the railway tracks for the city.
It required six years and 5,000 workers to finish. It was made by using red sandstone and marble."</string>

<string name="agrafort">"Agra Fort was begun by Akbar between 1565 and 1573. It is situated on the west bank of the Jumna River, about 2km upstream from the Taj Mahal (map). Akbar built the fort of sandstone; his grandson Shah Jahan, the builder of the Taj Mahal, constructed palaces of white marble within the fort itself. Shah Jahan was imprisoned in Agra Fort following the coup of his son, Aurangzeb, and died here in 1657.

Agra Fort is entered today at the south end, through a low outer wall and gate (shown here) built by Aurangzeb. Visitors then pass in succession through two of Akbar's gates, the Amar Singh and the Akbari, before finally gaining admittance to the fort proper. The original entrance to the fort was through the grander Delhi Gate in the west wall.

The behavior of Mogul rulers, towards members of their own family, was appalling by any modern standard. Besides overthrowing and imprisoning his father, Aurangzeb murdered two brothers and a nephew on his way to the throne; his father, Shah Jahan, had similarly killed one brother and two nephews during his own climb to power. In that time there were no fixed laws of succession, and the harem system provided all too many candidates for the throne; it was, literally, kill or be killed for eligible males of the royal family. There are many similar, and equally appalling, examples from places as far apart as ancient China, the Roman and Byzantine Empires, Egypt, the Ottoman Empire, and Medieval and Renaissance Europe.

The gate was originally tiled. Although the colorful tile has been lost, The inlay patterns remain in the stone into which they were set. For defensive reasons, this gate is placed perpendicular to the walls. After passing through here, the visitor has to enter yet another gate, the Akbari Darwaza, before reaching the inside of the fort.
Akbari Darwaza ("Akbars Gate") is the third and final gate that guards the south entrance to the fort. The gate pierces the fort's massive inner wall between these two protective towers, which still retain some traces of their original tiling.
This palace takes its name from Jahangir, but was built by Akbar sometime between 1560 and 1580. Lacking ground-story windows, it might have been used as a zenana. The large bowl in front was carved in 1611 from a single block of porphyry; it is variously said to have been used as a cistern, or as Jahangir's bathtub.
On the east side of the fort, this octagonal pavilion looks out across the Jumna River and countryside, and downstream to the Taj Mahal. It is said to be the tower where Shah Jahan was imprisoned. Next to the Burj in the photo left foreground is the rear of the Khas Mahal and its adjoining pavilions. Below are fortifications and the riverbank. The river was originally higher, reaching up to the base of the walls."</string>

<string name="esselworld">"The park is owned by Pan India Paryatan Pvt. Ltd. (PIPPL). EsselWorld along with its counterparts, Water Kingdom are stretched over 64 acres of land. Together, they are recognised as India’s Largest Amusement And Water Park as well as Asia’s Largest Theme Water Park.
EsselWorld is the largest amusement park in the country. It draws in an estimated 1.8 million visitors annually, of which approximately 300,000 are students.
EsselWorld is home to a variety of rides appropriate for individuals of all ages. It boasts of fourteen family rides, eleven adrenaline-pumping thrill rides and fifteen children’s rides.
part from the conventional features of a theme park such as rollercoasters and rides, EsselWorld is also host to Mumbai’s first ice skating rink, spanning 3400 square feet. The park maintains the rink’s temperature at a constant 4 degrees Celsius.
The dance floor is an added characteristic of the park that enables visitors to hold parties at the park. It enjoys colored lights, high definition audio, and a glass dance floor. To maintain it’s international demeanor the dance hall plays a fusion of Bollywood as well as Western music.
Additionally, the theme park also comprises a 6-lane bowling alley widely known as “Riki’s Rocking Alley”. The bowling alley consists of an in-built arcade as well as a restaurant, “Tandoori One”, which serves vegetarian Indian cuisine.[8] Other culinary options across EsselWorld include Southern Treat - serving traditional South Indian delicacies, Domino’s Pizza, Taipan Chinese restaurant, Ohh! Mumbai - a taste of the local favorites, Happy Singh Da Dhaba – Punjabi cuisine, Petu’s and Mother Dairy desserts."</string>

<string name="chawpattybeach">"Girgaon Chaupati', commonly known as just Chaupati (pronounced as chow-patty), is one of the most famous public beaches adjoining Marine Drive in the Girgaon area of Mumbai, India. The beach is famous for Ganesh Chaturthi celebrations when lakhs of people from all over Mumbai come to immerse the idols of Lord Ganapati in the Arabian Sea. It is also one of the many places in the city where the Ramlila is performed on a stage every year. An effigy of Ravan, that is erected on the sand, is burnt by the end of the 10-day performance. One can find several bhelpuri, panipuri, ragda patties and pav bhaji vendors on the beach.

On the road running along the beach, the lone surviving terrorist of the 26/11 attacks, Ajmal Kasab was caught and arrested. A bronze statue of Tukaram Omble, the cop who helped nab Kasab, was erected on 26/11/11.
Chowpatty is really Chau-pati (four channels or four creeks) as per (Bombay City Gazetteer, I. 27). This name is analogous to that of Satpaty, a village in the Mahim Taluka of the Thane District, which is approached through a Channel or Creek, containing seven divisions of water."</string>

<string name="karlacaves">"Karla is one of the most famous centres of early rock-cut architecture and has received much attention of scholars and commoners alike. The group of rock excavations is not that elaborate when compared to its counterparts at Ajanta and Ellora. However, the grand Chaitya griha of Karla is the grandest and the largest of all the chaita-grihas of India. The group at Karla consists of 16 rock cut excavations of which cave 8 is the chaityagriha which was caused during Satavahanas.

Karla is situated in Maval Taluka of Pune on the Pune-Mumbai highway, about 60 km northwest of Pune. The location of Karla is also important for its rich embellishments, it is on the ancient highway connecting seaports of Kalyan and Sopara to the cities located inland. The other nearest centre of great Buddhist activity is Bhaja, which is 8 km south of Karla. The caves are excavated nearly 100 metres on a high spur of the chain of hills on the north flank of the Indrayani valley. The chaitya griha is the most prominent and hence it dominates the remaining excavations. A wide and flat open area in front of the chaityagriha could have provided an ideal place for large gatherings of the followers of Buddhism. The wide land narrows down on the south and runs almost as a ledge path, turns east and continues up to the edge of the cliff. A few isolated excavations could also been seen near this ledge path.

The monasteries at Karla could be datable between circa 60-40 B.C. and 4th century A.D. Except from three excavations of Mahayana phase the remaining belong to the Hinayana phase. It seems that the entire monastic complex at Karla was conceived as a single design. The caves were caused from the donations and support of a group of assorted individuals. This includes a prince of Maharathi family; merchants and merchant guilds; monks and nuns and lay devotees including men and women. Persons practically from every strata of the society contributed towards the establishment of this complex thus indicating its importance in the Buddhist world. The various inscriptions found here clearly speaks of 27 individuals from various places like Vejamti (Banavasi, north Kanara district, nearly 600 km south of Karla); Sopara (nearly 100 km northwest of Karla) and unidentified towns of Umehanakata and Dhenukakata. Most of the donors from Dhenukakata were Yavanas.

The inscriptions of Usavadata and Vasisthiputra Pulumavi mention donation of land to the Veluraka Samgha. The inscription of Pulumavi is dated in his 24th year of his reign (A.D. 154). The inscriptions thus give the ancient name of Karla as ‘Veluraka’. "</string>

<string name="elephantcaves">"The Elephanta Caves (natively known as Gharapurichi Leni) are a network of sculpted caves located on Elephanta Island, or Gharapuri (literally "the city of caves") in Mumbai Harbour, 10 kilometres (6.2 mi) to the east of the city of Mumbai in the Indian state of Maharashtra. The island, located on an arm of the Arabian Sea, consists of two groups of caves—the first is a large group of five Hindu caves, the second, a smaller group of two Buddhist caves. The Hindu caves contain rock cut stone sculptures, representing the Shaiva Hindu sect, dedicated to the Lord Shiva.[1][2]

The rock cut architecture of the caves has been dated to between the 5th and 8th centuries, although the identity of the original builders is still a subject of debate. The caves are hewn from solid basalt rock. All the caves were also originally painted in the past, but now only traces remain.

The main cave (Cave 1, or the Great Cave) was a Hindu place of worship until Portuguese rule began in 1534, after which the caves suffered severe damage. This cave was renovated in the 1970s after years of neglect, and was designated a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1987 to preserve the artwork. It is currently maintained by the Archaeological Survey of India (ASI)."</string>

<string name="gatewayofindia">"The Gateway of India is synonymous with Mumbai. It is the most famous monument of Mumbai and is the starting point for most tourists who want to explore the city. Gateway of India is a great historical monument built during the British rule in the country. It was built as a triumphal arch to commemorate the visit of King George V and Queen Mary to Mumbai (then, Bombay). Gateway of India was built at Apollo Bunder, a popular meeting place. It was designed by the British architect, George Wittet.

The foundation stone of the Gateway of India was laid down by the then Governor of Bombay (Mumbai) on March 31st 1913. The archway is 26 meters high and joined with four turrets and intricate latticework carved on stones. The arch alone was built at the cost of 21 lakhs. It is built in Indo-Sarcenic style, though some influence of Gujarati style is also evident in its architecture. The structure itself is quite majestic and a hybrid of the Arc de Triomphe in Paris.

In the past Gateway of India used to be the arrival point for visitors from the west. Ironically, when the Raj ended in 1947, this colonial symbol also became a sort of epitaph: the last of the British ships that set sail for England left from the Gateway. Today this symbol of colonialism has got Indianised, drawing droves of local tourists and citizens. This landmark of Mumbai is a must visit of the city.

The Gateway faces the vast Arabian Sea, flanked by Mumbai's another attraction, Marine Drive, a road running parallel to the sea. The majestic monument is a must-visit at night, in its pristine glory against the backdrop of the sea. It is visited by millions of people across the world every year and is a very significant figure in the lives of the people of Mumbai, as the Gateway defines the grandeur of the city that is a culmination of both, historic and modern cultural environment."</string>

<string name="amerfort">"Amer Palace (Hindi: ???? ?????, also spelled and pronounced as Amber) is located in Amer, a town with an area of 4 square kilometres (1.5 sq mi)located 11 kilometres (6.8 mi) from Jaipur, Rajasthan state, India. Located high on a hill, it is the principal tourist attractions in the Jaipur area. The town of Amer was originally built by Meenas, and later it was ruled by Raja Man Singh.

Amer Fort is known for its artistic Hindu style elements. With its large ramparts and series of gates and cobbled paths, the fort overlooks Maota Lake.

The aesthetic ambiance of the palace is seen within its walls. Constructed of red sandstone and marble, the attractive, opulent palace is laid out on four levels, each with a courtyard. It consists of the Diwan-e-Aam, or "Hall of Public Audience", the Diwan-e-Khas, or "Hall of Private Audience", the Sheesh Mahal (mirror palace), or Jai Mandir, and the Sukh Niwas where a cool climate is artificially created by winds that blow over a water cascade within the palace. Hence, the Amer Fort is also popularly known as the Amer Palace.[4] The palace was the residence of the Rajput Maharajas and their families. At the entrance to the palace near the fort's Ganesh Gate, there is a temple dedicated to Sila Devi, a goddess of the Chaitanya cult, which was given to Raja Man Singh when he defeated the Raja of Jessore, Bengal in 1604. (Jessore is now in Bangladesh).

This palace, along with Jaigarh Fort, is located immediately above on the Cheel ka Teela (Hill of Eagles) of the same Aravalli range of hills. The palace and Jaigarh Fort are considered one complex, as the two are connected by a subterranean passage. This passage was meant as an escape route in times of war to enable the royal family members and others in the Amer Fort to shift to the more redoubtable Jaigarh Fort.

Annual tourist visitation to the Amer Palace was reported by the Superintendent of the Department of Archaeology and Museums as 5000 visitors a day, with 1.4 million visitors during 2007.

At the 37th session of the World Heritage Committee held in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, in 2013, Amer Fort, along with five other forts of Rajasthan, was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site as part of the group Hill Forts of Rajasthan."</string>

<string name="chittorgarh">"Chittorgarh Fort (Hindi/Rajasthani: ???????? ????? Chittor Durg) is one of the largest forts in India and probably the grandest in the state of Rajasthan. It is a World Heritage Site. The fort, popularly known as Chittor, was the capital of Mewar and is today situated in Chittorgarh City. It was initially ruled by Guhilot and later by Sisodias, the Suryavanshi clans of Chattari Rajputs, from the 7th century, until it was finally abandoned in 1568 after the siege by Emperor Akbar in 1567. It sprawls majestically over a hill 180 m (590.6 ft) in height spread over an area of 280 ha (691.9 acres) above the plains of the valley drained by the Berach River. The fort precinct with an evocative history is studded with a series of historical palaces, gates, temples and two prominent commemoration towers. These monumental ruins have inspired the imagination of tourists and writers for centuries.

The fort was sacked three times between the 15th and 16th centuries; in 1303 Allauddin Khilji defeated Rana Ratan Singh, in 1535 Bahadur Shah, the Sultan of Gujarat defeated Bikramjeet Singh and in 1567 Emperor Akbar defeated Maharana Udai Singh II who left the fort and founded Udaipur. Each time the men fought bravely rushing out of the fort walls charging the enemy but lost every time. Following these defeats, Jauhar was committed thrice by more than 13,000 ladies and children of the Rajput heroes who laid their lives in battles at Chittorgarh Fort, first led by Rani Padmini wife of Rana Rattan Singh who was killed in the battle in 1303, and later by Rani Karnavati in 1537 AD.

Thus, the fort represents the quintessence of tribute to the nationalism, courage, medieval chivalry and sacrifice exhibited by the Mewar rulers of Sisodia and their kinsmen and women and children, between the 7th and 16th centuries. The rulers, their soldiers, the women folk of royalty and the commoners considered death as a better option than dishonor in the face of surrender to the foreign invading armies.

In 2013, at the 37th session of the World Heritage Committee held in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, Chittorgarh Fort, along with 5 other forts of Rajasthan, was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site under the group Hill Forts of Rajasthan."</string>

<string name="jaisalmer">"Jaisalmer Fort is one of the largest fortifications in the world. It is situated in the city of Jaisalmer, in the Indian state of Rajasthan. It is a World Heritage Site. It was built in 1156 AD by the Rajput ruler Rawal Jaisal, from whom it derives its name. (Rawal Jaisal's son was Shalivahan II; Manj and Bhati Rajputs are descended from him.) The fort stands amidst the sandy expanse of the great Thar Desert, on Trikuta Hill, and has been the scene of many battles. Its massive yellow sandstone walls are a tawny lion colour during the day, fading to honey-gold as the sun sets, thereby camouflaging the fort in the yellow desert. For this reason, it is also known as the Sonar Quila or Golden Fort.[1] The fort is located in the very heart of the city, and is one of the most notable monuments in the locality.

In 2013, at the 37th session of the World Heritage Committee held in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, Jaisalmer Fort, along with 5 other forts of Rajasthan, was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site under the group Hill Forts of Rajasthan.The fort was built by Rawal Jaiswal in 1156 CE. Jaisal conspired with the Sultan of Gaur to dispose his nephew Bhojdev from his territory. The other important event of the fort was during 1276 when King Jetsi strengthened the fort against the invading Sultan of Delhi. the 56 bastions were manned by 3,700 soldiers. After eight years of invasion, the Sultan's army destroyed the castle. Bhatis took control of the fort, but had no means to strengthen it. In 1306, Dodoo was elected the Rawal for his bravery for ejecting the Rathors. He subsequently started building the fort. The Rawals could not stand the invasion of Mughal emperor Babur and subsequently seeded to Akbar in 1570 and also got his daughter married to him."</string>

<string name="ghantaghar">"Ghanta Ghar also known as the clock tower of Rajasthan was constructed by the Late Shri Sardar Singh Ji of Jodhpur.Beside the tower, there in the Sadar Market that is frequented by tourists on shopping spree. From this market, tourists can purchase Rajasthani textiles, clay figurines, miniature camels and elephants, marble inlay work and classic silver jewellery."</string>


<string name="jalmahal">"Jal Mahal (meaning Water Palace) is a palace located in the middle of the Man Sagar Lake in Jaipur city, the capital of the state of Rajasthan, India. The palace and the lake around it were renovated and enlarged in the 18th century by Maharaja Jai Singh II of Amber.The Jal Mahal palace has got an eye-popping makeover. Traditional boat-makers from Vrindavan have crafted the Rajput style wooden boats. A gentle splashing of oars on the clear lake waters takes you to Jal Mahal. You move past decorated hallways and chambers on the first floor to climb all the way up to the fragrant Chameli Bagh. Across the lake, you can view the Aravalli hills, dotted with temples and ancient forts, and on the other side, bustling Jaipur. The most remarkable change is in the lake itself. The drains were diverted, two million tonnes of toxic silt were dredged from the bottom, increasing its depth by over a metre, a water treatment system was developed, local vegetation and fish reintroduced, the surrounding wetlands regenerated and five nesting islands created to attract migratory birds.
he lake, situated to the north of Jaipur city lies between Amer, the historic city and Jaipur, the provincial headquarters of Rajasthan state. It has a water spread area of 300 acres (121 ha) and is enclosed by the Aravalli hills on the north, west and eastern sides, while the southern side consists of plains that are intensely inhabited. There is the Nahargarh Fort (Nahargarh meaning home of tigers) in the hills that provides a commanding view of the Man Sagar Lake and the Jal Mahal palace, in addition to a beautiful view of the city of Jaipur. The lake was created by constructing a dam across the Darbhawati River, between Khilagarh hills and the hilly areas of Nahargarh, in the 16th century. The drainage area of the lake is 23.5 square kilometres (9.1 sq mi)contributed by an urban area accounting for 50 percent and hilly terrain accounting for the balance, being degraded Aravalli hills, which have added to the siltation problem in the lake. A rain fall average of 657.4 millimetres (25.88 in) per year (90% of this rainfall occurs during the months of June to September) in the catchment contributes to the storage in the reservoir. At the outlet end of the dam there is an irrigation system that is supplied with water stored in the reservoir (obligatory water demand for this is reported to be 2,410,000 cubic metres during the five months from November to March). Two large nalas (streams) that also drain the surrounding Nahargarh hills and Jaipur are the Brahmpuri and Nagtalai, which bring in large amounts of untreated sewage, in addition to solid wastes. The hills surrounding the lake area, towards the north east of Jaipur, have quartzite rock formations (with a thin layer of soil cover), which is part of Aravalli hills range. Rock exposures on the surface in some parts of the project area have also been utilised for constructing buildings. From the north east, the Kanak Vrindavan valley, where a temple complex is situated, the hills slope gently towards the lake edge. Within the lake area, the ground area is made up of a thick mantle of soil, blown sand and alluvium. Forest denudation, particularly in the hilly areas, has caused soil erosion, compounded by wind and water action. Due to this, silt built up in the lake resulting in a raising of the bed level of the lake."</string>


<string name="bhagsunagfalls">"Also called Bhagsu Falls, this site houses the famous Bhagsunath Temple, dedicated to Lord Shiva. This is a famous tourist attraction and also an important place for Hindu pilgrims. 

The cascading waterfalls, about 20 metres in height, are an absolute marvel to look at, especially during the monsoons. There is a nice cafeteria next to the falls and the area serve as an excellent picnic spot for tourists. Bhagsunag Falls are located about 2 kilometres away from McLeodganj and are best visit while on a trek, although you can also drive up to Bhagsu village."</string>

<string name="bhrigulake">"Bhrigu Lake is a lake located at an elevation of around 4,300 metres (14,100 ft) in Kullu district, Himachal Pradesh, India. It is located to the east of Rohtang Pass and is around 6 kilometres (3.7 mi) from Gulaba village. It can be reached by trekking either from the Vashishth temple, which is famous for its hot water springs, which is close to the town of Manali or from Gulaba village. Actually there is no settlement in Gulaba and is actually an area of the Pir Panjal mountain range. It is named after Maharishi Bhrigu.

Legend has it that the sage used to mediate near the lake and hence it has been rendered sacred; the locals believe that due to this the lake never freezes completely.
    "</string>

<string name="hadimbatemple">"Hidimbi Devi Temple, also known variously as the Hadimba Temple, is located in Manali, a hill station in the State of Himachal Pradesh in north India.It is an ancient cave temple dedicated to Hidimbi Devi, sister of Hidimba, a figure in the Indian epic Mahabharata. The temple is surrounded by a cedar forest at the foot of the Himalayas. The sanctuary is built over a huge rock jutting out of the ground which was worshipped as an image of the deity. The structure was built in 1553. 
The Hidimbi Devi temple is built around a cave where Hidimba performed meditation. Hidimba was supposed to have lived there with her brother Hidimb, and not much is known about their parents. Born into a Rakshas family, Hidimba vowed to marry one who would defeat her brother Hidimb, who was supposed to be very brave and fearless. During the Pandava's exile, when they visited Manali; Bhima, one of the five Pandavas, killed Hidimb. Thereafter, Hidimba married Bhima and gave birth to their son Ghatotkacha.
The Hidimbi Devi Temple has intricately carved wooden doors and a 24 meters tall wooden "shikhar" or tower above the sanctuary. The tower consists of three square roofs covered with timber tiles and a fourth brass cone-shaped roof at the top. The earth goddess Durga forms the theme of the main door carvings. The temple base is made out of whitewashed, mud-covered stonework. An enormous rock occupies the inside of the temple, only a 7.5 cm (3 inch) tall brass image representing goddess Hidimbi Devi. A rope hangs down in front of the rock,and according to a legend,in bygone days religious zealots would tie the hands of "sinners" by the rope and then swing them against the rock.
About seventy metres away from the temple, there is a shrine dedicated to Goddess Hidimbi's son, Ghatotkacha, who was born after she married Bhima. The most surprising feature of the temple or what believers could call the most reassuring feature of the temple is the fact that inside the temple the imprint of the feet of the Goddess carved on a block of stone are worshipped and, when zooming into the area where the temple is located via Google Satellite, the imprint of a giant foot spanning across the valley in the area near the temple can be seen."</string>

<string name="chintpurnitemple">"Chintpurni is a major pilgrimage center and one of the Shakti Peethas in India. The Chintpurni shakti peeth (Chhinnamastika shakti peeth) is located in Una district Himachal Pradesh state, surrounded by the western Himalaya in the north and east in the smaller Shiwalik (or Shivalik) range bordering the state of Punjab. The Chintpurni Shakti Peeth is dedicated to the temple of Chinnamastika Devi or Chinnamasta Devi. Chhinnamasta or Chinnamastika temple is one of the 7 major and 51 total Shakti Peethas. Here, Chhinnamasta is interpreted as the severed-headed one as well as the foreheaded-one.
When Lord Vishnu cut up the body of Sati into 51 pieces so that Lord Shiva would calm down and stop his Tandava, the pieces were scattered over various places in the Indian subcontinent. It is believed that parts of Sati’s Forehead fell at this place and is thus considered one of the most important of the 51 Shakti Peethas.

The goddess resident in Chintpurni is also known by the name of Chhinnamastika. According to Markandeya Purana, goddess Chandi defeated the demons after a fierce battle but two of her yogini emanations (Jaya and Vijaya) were still thirsty for more blood. Goddess Chandi cut off her own head to quench Jaya and Vijaya’s thirst for more blood.

She is usually shown holding her own severed head in her hand, drinking one stream of blood spurting from the arteries in her neck, while at her side are two naked yoginis, each of whom drinks another stream of blood.

Chhinnamasta, the headless goddess, is the Great Cosmic Power who helps the sincere and devoted yogi to dissolve his or her mind, including all the preconceived ideas, attachments and habits into the Pure Divine Consciousness. Cutting off the head suggests the separation of the mind from the body, that is the freedom of the consciousness from the material confines of the physical body.

According to Puranic traditions, Chhinnamastika Devi will be protected by Shiva - Rudra Mahadev in the four directions. There are four Shiva temples - Kaleshwar Mahadev in the east, Narayhana Mahadev in the west, Muchkund Mahadev in the north and Shiva Bari in the south - which are nearly equidistant from Chintpurni. This also confirms Chintpurni as the abode of Chhinnamastika Devi."</string>

<string name="kalkashimlarailway">"The Kalka–Shimla Railway is a 2 ft 6 in (762 mm) narrow gauge railway in North-West India travelling along a mostly mountainous route from Kalka to Shimla. It is known for dramatic views of the hills and surrounding villages.
The Kalka–Shimla Railway was built to connect Shimla, the summer capital of India during the British Raj, with the Indian rail system. Now, Shimla is the capital city of Himachal Pradesh and Kalka is a town in the Panchkula district of Haryana. The route is famous for its scenery and improbable construction.
Originally 107 tunnels were built on Kalka Shimla Railway Track and 102 remain in use. The longest tunnel is at Barog. Engineer Colonel Barog dug the tunnel from both ends and could not align them and was symbolically fined one rupee. He couldn't live with the shame and committed suicide inside the incomplete tunnel. Chief Engineer H.S. Herlington later completed the tunnel with help from Bhalku, a local sadhu.
The line has 864 bridges. The railway has a ruling gradient of 1 in 33 or 3%. It has 919 curves, the sharpest being 48 degrees (a radius of 37.47 m or 122.93 feet). Climbing from 656 meters (2,152 ft), the line terminates at an elevation of 2,076 meters (6,811 ft) at Shimla. The line originally used 42 lb/yd (21 kg/m) rail but this was later relaid to 60 lb/yd (30 kg/m) rail."</string>

<string name="rohtangpass">"Rohtang Pass, is a high mountain pass on the eastern Pir Panjal Range of the Himalayas around 51 km from Manali. It connects the Kullu Valley with the Lahaul and Spiti Valleys of Himachal Pradesh, India.Rohtang Pass (Bhoti: Rohtang , lit: pile of corpses, due to people dying in bad weather trying to cross the pass) (elevation 3,978 m (13,050 ft)), is a high mountain pass on the eastern Pir Panjal Range of the Himalayas around 51 km (32 mi) from Manali. It connects the Kullu Valley with the Lahaul and Spiti Valleys of Himachal Pradesh, India. Manali-Leh Highway, a part of NH 21, transverses Rohtang Pass.
The pass provides a natural divide between the humid Kullu Valley with a primarily Hindu culture (in the south), and the arid high-altitude Lahaul and Spiti valleys with a Buddhist culture (in the north). The pass lies on the watershed between the Chenab and Beas basins. On the southern side of this pass, the Beas River emerges from underground and flows southward[6] and on its northern side, the Chandra River (flows from the eastern Himalayas), a source stream of the river Chenab, flows westward.
The pass is open from May to November. It is not particularly high or difficult to cross on foot by Himalayan standards, but it has a well-deserved reputation for being dangerous because of unpredictable snowstorms and blizzards.With increase in Traffic at Rohtang Valley, Environmentalists fear its impact on the fragile mountain ecology. Rise in Average Temperature and consequent melting of glaciers are also issues of severe concern."</string>

<string name="ridgeshimla">"The Ridge road is a large open space, located in the heart of Shimla, the capital city of Himachal Pradesh, India. The Ridge is the hub of all cultural activities of Shimla. It is situated along the Mall Road, which is the famous shopping center of Shimla. Most major places of Shimla like Snowdon, Mall, Jakhoo hill, etc. are connected through the Ridge.

It runs east to west alongside the Mall Road, and joins it at the Scandal Point on the west side. On the east side, The Ridge road leads to Lakkar Bazaar, a wooden crafts market. It's the major landmark and the most easily recognized face of the hill station. When winter sets in and when the country had its first major snowfall of the year, most news papers printed photos of the ridge submerged in clumps of fresh snow.

Prominent landmarks on the Ridge are a neo-Gothic structure of Church from 1844 and a tudorbethan styled library building built in 1910. There are three statues on the ridge; that of Mahatma Gandhi, Indira Gandhi, and Dr. Y.S. Parmar, the first chief minister of Himachal Pradesh.

The biggest hillstation of the world, at one time the base ridge of Shimla had the thickest forest of the area, now the green slopes are covered with firs, pines, the Himalayan oak and carmine rhododendron trees, among which are dotted red-roofed chalets, half-timbered houses and Gothic Government buildings are visible from The Ridge.
The Ridge houses a large water reservoir which acts as the main supply of Shimla town. The main water supply of Shimla comes from this tank."</string>

<string name="bahubali">"Bahubali (English: one with strong arms) was the son of Rishabha, the first tirthankara and founder of Jainism in the present half-cycle of time. Bahubali is a much revered figure among Jains. After winning the nonviolent duel with his elder brother, Bharata, he developed a desire for renunciation. He gave his kingdom to Bharata and became a Jain monk. Bahubali meditated motionless for a whole year in kayotsarga posture because of which climbers grew around his legs. After one year of meditation, he attained Kevala Jnana (omniscience) and became an arihant. A human being who destroys all inner passions like anger, attachment, greed and pride is revered as an arihant. According to Jain texts, he attained moksha at mount Kailasa and became a Siddha i.e., soul at its purest form (or a liberated soul).
Bahubali is also called Gommatesh because of the statue dedicated to him. "Gommateshwara" statue, built by the Ganga dynasty minister and commander Chamundaraya, is a 57-foot (17 m) monolith and is situated above a hill in Shravanabelagola, in the Hassan district of Karnataka state, India. It was built in around 983 A.D. and is one of the largest free standing statues in the world. On August 5, 2007, the statue was voted by Indians as the first of Seven Wonders of India; 49 percent of the total votes went in favor of it."</string>

<string name="bidarfort">"Bidar Fort is situated in Bidar city of the northern plateau of Karnataka, India. The fort, the city and the district are all affixed with the name Bidar. Sultan Alla-Ud-Din Bahman of the Bahmanid Dynasty shifted his capital from Gulbarga to Bidar in 1427 and built his fort along with a number of Islamic monuments. There are over 30 monuments inside Bidar fort.
Bidar city and fort are located on the edge of the Bidar platueau, the northernmost plateau in Karnataka state. The plateau area, comprising low laterite hills, end to the north at the Manjira River, a major tributary of the Godavari River. The Karanja River, a sub-tributary, drains the surrounding low-lying areas and feeds into the Manjiri River. Bidar district comprises the only part of the Godavari basin in Karnataka.

Geologically, Bidar district is predominantly Deccan Trap with underlying layers of gneiss emerging along the eastern boundary.The plateau has an altitude of 2,200 feet (670 m), and measures 22 miles (35 km) in length and 12 miles (19 km) in width at its broadest.The plateau encompasses a total area of 190 square kilometres (73 sq mi). Bidar fort is built in the form of an irregular rhombus on the edge of the plateau with sheer walls built along the North and the East.

The ancient capital Kalyani (Basavakalyan) of the Western Chalukya Empire is situated about 40 miles (64 km) to the west of Bidar.

Bidar fort is considered to have been built during the reign of the Western Chalukya dynasty which was established in 977 AD at Kalyani. Subsequently, it was captured by the Yadava dynasty of Devagiri and fell yet again, to the Kakatiyas of Warangal. Architectural relics of the Hindu period, such as the shrine to Goddess Bhawani and the Vira Sangayya temple, can still be seen in the fort."</string>

<string name="kudremukh">"Kudremukh also spelled Kuduremukha is a mountain range and name of a peak located in Chikkamagaluru district, in Karnataka, India. It is also the name of a small hill station cum mining town situated near the mountain, about 48 kilometres from Karkala and around 20 kilometres from Kalasa. The name Kuduremukha literally means horse-face (in the Kannada language) and refers to a particular picturesque view of a side of the mountain that resembles a horses face. It was also referred to as Samseparvata, historically since it was approached from Samse village. Kuduremukh is Karnatakas 3rd highest peak after Mullayangiri and Baba Budangiri. The nearest airport is Mangalore International Airport at Mangalore which is at distance of 99 kilometres.
The Kudremukh National Park is the second largest Wildlife Protected Area (600.32 km²) belonging to a tropical wet evergreen type of forest in the Western Ghats. Kudremukh National Park is located in Dakshina Kannada, Udupi District and Chikkamagaluru districts of the State of Karnataka. The Western Ghats is one of the thirty four hotspots identified for bio-diversity conservation in the world. Kudremukh National Park comes under the Global Tiger Conservation Priority-I, under the format developed jointly by the Wildlife Conservation Society (WCS) and World Wide Fund-USA.Kudremukh National Park is spread partly over the thick hilly forests near the coastal plains on the western portion and the shola vegetation on the Western Ghats uplands, covering parts of three districts, viz., Chickmagalur, Udupi and Dakshina Kannada. The Kudremukh peak, by which the national park derives its name, is the highest spot at 1892 meters."</string>

<string name="mullayanagiri">"Mulayyanagiri is the highest peak in Karnataka, India. Mullayyanagiri is located at 13°23'26?N 75°43'18?E in the Chandra Dhrona Hill Ranges of the Western Ghats of Chikkamagaluru Taluk. With a height of 1,930 metres (6,330 ft), it is the highest peak between the Himalayas and the Nilgiris. Mullayanagiri is one of the best trekking places in Karnataka and South India. The Sunset presents a spectacular view from the peak. The summit of Mullayanagiri also houses a police radio relay station.
The peak gets its name from a small temple (gadduge/tomb) at the summit, which is dedicated to a Tapasvi "Mulappa swamy" who, is believed to have meditated at the caves only a couple of feet below the summit. The caves are accessible and not very deep, they have a direct entrance to the garbagudi of the temple, which is now blocked by the temple priests. Apart from multiple versions of folklore and strong Siddha culture around the belt, the origins or any information about the deity remains ambiguous.
Anciently, when the present asphalt roads and the 300 concrete steps were not present, a trail was used to reach the peak, known as 'Sarpadari' or 'sarpanadi'. Although it is not very frequently visited now, this trail is cherished by trekkers."</string>

<string name="mysorezoo">"Mysore Zoo (officially the Sri Chamarajendra Zoological Gardens) is a 157-acre (64 ha) zoo located near the palace in Mysore, India. It is one of the oldest and most popular zoos in India, and is home to a wide range of species(168-species). Mysore Zoo is one of the city’s most popular attractions.

While mainly depending on entry fees for its financing, an adoption scheme introduced in the early 2000s at Mysore Zoo has been a success, with Celebrities, Institutions, and animal lovers contributing directly to the welfare of the zoo inmates.

Mysore Zoo was originally created in 1892 on 10 acres (4.0 ha) of the summer palace of Maharaja Sri Chamaraja Wodeyar, and was originally called the Palace Zoo. The zoo was originally set up by G.H. Krumbeigal, a German landscaper and horticulturist. Over the next 10 years the zoo was expanded to 45 acres (18 ha) with spacious enclosures that are still in use.
The zoo was opened to the public in 1902, and now includes a bandstand and an artificial lake. It was given to the Department of Parks and Gardens of the Mysore State Government in 1948. The zoo was expanded first with another 50 acres (20 ha), and then another 150 acres (61 ha) with the acquisition of the Karanji Tank (Karanji reservoir), in which an artificial island has been created as a sanctuary for birds.
The Zoo had completed 100 years in 1992. The Centenary celebrations were held in 1990-91. During centenary celebrations various developmental activities were initiated such as renovation and modification of entrance gate, Hospital building, Walk Through Reptiles, etc., The bust of Sri Chamarajendra Wadiyar, founder of Mysore Zoo was unveiled. The Logo of Zoo, Centenary Souvenir, publication of Literature and Leaflets, conducting various Competitions, Preparation of a documentary film were other highlights."</string>

<string name="ranganathittubirdsanctuary">"Ranganathittu Bird Sanctuary also known as Pakshi Kashi of Karnataka is a bird sanctuary in the Mandya District of the state of Karnataka in India. It is the largest bird sanctuary in the state, only 0.67 km2. in area, which is about 40 acres and comprises six islets on the banks of the Kaveri river. Ranganathittu is located three kilometers away from the historic town of Srirangapatna and 16 kilometres (9.9 mi) north of Mysore. The sanctuary attracted about 2.90 lakh visitors during 2011-12, which shows its notability as important bird sanctuary of India.
    Roughly 170 birds have been recorded here. Of these, the painted stork, Asian openbill stork, common spoonbill, woolly-necked stork, black-headed ibis, lesser whistling duck, Indian shag, stork-billed kingfisher, egret, cormorant, Oriental darter, and heron breed here regularly. The great stone plover, and river tern also nest here. The park is home to a large flock of streak-throated swallows.[5] During the months of January and February, more than 30 species of birds are found and the season of the sanctuary is from November to June. About 50 pelicans have made Ranganathittu as their permanent home."</string>
 
<string name="mahabodhitemple">"The Mahabodhi Temple  (Literally: "Great Awakening Temple"), a UNESCO World Heritage Site, is a Buddhist temple in Bodh Gaya, marking the location where Siddhartha Gautama, the Buddha, is said to have attained enlightenment. Bodh Gaya (located in Gaya district) is located about 96 km (60 mi) from Patna, Bihar state, India.

The complex was primarily a Mahayana site.Images of the site include Padmapani, Avalokitesvara, Vajrapani, Khasarpana, Tara, Marichi, Yamantaka, Jambhala and Vajravarahi.[2] Images of Vishnu, Mahadeva, Surya and other Vedic deities are also associated with the site.
Traditional accounts say that, around 530 BC, Siddhartha Gautama, a young prince who saw the suffering of the world and wanted to end it, reached the forested banks of the Phalgu river, near the city of Gaya, India. There he sat in meditation under a peepul tree (Ficus religiosa or Sacred Fig) which later became known as the Bodhi tree. According to Buddhist scriptures, after three days and three nights, Siddharta attained enlightenment and the answers that he had sought. In that location, Mahabodhi Temple was built by Emperor Ashoka in around 260 BC.[3]

The Buddha then spent the succeeding seven weeks at seven different spots in the vicinity meditating and considering his experience. Several specific places at the current Mahabodhi Temple relate to the traditions surrounding these seven weeks"</string>

<string name="mahavirmandir">"Mahavir Mandir  is one of the holiest Hindu temples dedicated to Lord Hanuman, located in Patna, Bihar, India. Million of pilgrims visit the temple every year and is the second most visited religious shrine in North India. Acharya Kishore Kunal is the secretary of the Mahavir Mandir Temple Trust, Patna.
The Mahavir Mandir Trusts have the second highest budget in North India after the famous Maa Vaishno Devi shrine. The earning of Mahavir Mandir has gone now up to an average of ?1 lakh per day.
The first establishment date of temple is unknown. This temple gained popularity in 1947 with large number of Hindu refugees coming to Patna after the partition of India. Subsequently temple was rebuilt as a concrete house at same time. Even this was broken down in 1987 to make a huge marble temple. The idol of Sankat-Mochan stands in it.
Mahavir Mandir Trusts is named Shri Mahavir Sthan Nyas Samiti and monitors working and development of temple. The Trusts also runs human welfare organization like Mahavir Cancer Institute and Research Centre, Mahavir Vaatsalya Hospital and Mahavir Arogya Hospital and several hospitals and orphanage in the agricultural and rural state of Bihar. The trust has submitted its 2008-09 budget, which is of 35.13 crore. Floating stone has been brought in from famous ramsetu which never sinks in water. It is there for public exhibition."</string>

<string name="patandevi">"Patan Devi , also called Maa Patneshwari, is the oldest and one of the most sacred temples of Patna. It is regarded as one of the 51 Siddha Shakti Pithas in India. According to Puranic legends, the 'right thigh' of the corpse of Sati had fallen here when it was chopped off by Lord Vishnu with his 'Sudarshan Chakra'. The ancient temple, originally called Maa Sarvanand Kari Patneshwari, is believed to be the abode of the goddess Durga.

The name of the city Patna is widely believed to have been derived from the name of the Bari Patan Devi Temple. Some however doubt whether the name of Patna is derived from this temple. According to them the name is derived from patan which means a town and Patna was a big place of export and import.
According to the Hindu mythology, it is believed that the right thigh of Devi Sati fell in Magadh and it is said that the part of the body of Sati fell in both Maharajganj and Chowk areas in Old Patna city. At these places, the Badi Patan Devi temple and the Chhoti Patan Devi temple were built. According to the Tantra Charumani, the small images of the Bari Patan Devi Temple, Patna are the Goddess Mahakali, Mahalakshmi and Mahasaraswati. In Hindu mythology, these Goddesses protected Putraka, who was the founder of Pataliputra. A strange stone image has been found in a tank near the Bari Patan Devi Temple, Patna. That image has been kept in the eastern veranda of the main temple where this stone is being worshiped regularly."</string>

<string name="patnamuseum">"Patna Museum is the state museum of the Indian state of Bihar. Built in 1917 during the British Times to house the historical artefacts found in the vicinity of Patna, it is in the style of Mughal and Rajput architecture and is known locally as the Jadu Ghar.
The Museum was constructed by the British to conserve and display the historical artifacts found in the vicinity of the state capital. The concept of having a museum arose in 1912, after Bihar and Bengal were separated. Patna Museum started functioning in 1915 from the commissioner's bungalow, on the campus of A N Sinha Institute.

The artifacts were then shifted to a new rooms of Patna High Court building before being taken to the present building in 1929. the land of present building was selected on Patna-Gaya road (now Budh Marg) in 1925. The two storeyed building, designed by Rai Bahadur Bishnu Swarup, was completed in 1928.[3] It was opened as the first museum of Bihar and Orissa Province by then Governor of Bihar and Orissa Sir Hugh Lansdown Stephenson.
Items on display in the multipurpose museum include archaeological objects, coins, art objects, paintings, instruments, textiles, paintings, thankas, bronze images and sculptures and terra cotta images by Hindu and Buddhist artists.[1] It has a rare collection of British-period paintings depicting day-to-day life, as well as a fine collection related to the first President of India, Dr. Rajendra Prasad. It also houses a First World War cannon.[4]

The fossil of a tree said to be more than 200 million years old is on display,[1] as is a casket — unearthed in 1958 by archaeologist A. S. Altekar at the Relic Stupa of Vaishali — said to contain the sacred ashes (relics) of Gautama Buddha.[5] The world-famous Didarganj Yakshi statue, discovered on a Ganges riverbank in 1917, is the museum's most prized collection.[1]

Beginning November 2009, a project was started to build a replacement museum in Patna to enable the display of larger collections of up to 20,000 objects."</string>

<string name="vishnupadmandir">"The Vishnupada Mandir  is the ancient temple in Gaya, India. It is a Hindu temple, dedicated to Lord Vishnu.

This temple is located along the Falgu River, marked by a footprint of Lord Vishnu known as Dharmasila, incised into a block of basalt. The Bhumihar Brahmins have been the traditional priests at Vishnupad Mandir in Gaya as Gayawar Pandas and in the adjoining districts like Hazaribagh.[3] Several legendary saints as Ramanujacharya, Madhvacharya, Sankaradeva and Chaitanya Mahaprabhu have visited this shrine.
The construction date of temple is unknown and it is believed that Rama along with Sita had visited this place. The present day structure was rebuilt by Devi Ahilya Bai Holkar, the ruler of Indore, in 1787,[5] on the banks of the Falgu river. A flight of 1000 stone steps leads to the top of the Brahmajuni hill, 1 km southwest of the Vishnupad mandir. Visitors prefer to go to the top of Brahmajuni hill see magnificent view of temple from top. There are many small temples near this temple.
This place is also believed to be the one under which the Lord Buddha meditated for six years.
Inside the Vishnupada Mandir, the 40 cm long footprint of Lord Vishnu is imprinted on solid rock and surrounded by a silver plated basin.
There is a gold flag and couple of Kalash made of gold has been embedded at the top of the temple which use to always glitter. It is said that long ago two thieves tried to steal the golden flag and the kalash from the top of the temple, but one thief became stone at the top of the temple and the other became stone as he fell to the ground. The stone of the thieves still remains on public view (it is not a man shape but a flat shape of the thieves)."</string>

<string name="cheraibeach">"Cherai Beach is located in Paravur Taluk, Kerala, India. Cherai Beach is just 25 km from Kochi, and 30 km from Cochin International Airport. The nearest towns are North Paravur (6 km) and Kodungallur (10 km) and the nearest railway station is Aluva (20 km).
Cherai has played an important role in the history of modern Kerala by becoming the birthplace of two prominent political personsages of modern Kerala - Mathai Manjooran and Sahodaran Ayyappan.

Cherai Gowreeshwara Temple is one of the main Hindu temple. Temple is mainatained by Vijnana Vardhini Sabha (V. V Sabha). It also known as Kerala palani. The festival in the temple is biggest festival in Eranakulam district. The festival happens every year towards the last 2 weeks of January or first 2 weeks of February. The main attractions are Elephant march(around 20-30 elephants).

There is one more famous temple in Cherai, which is Azheekkal Sree Varaha Temple famous for its beautiful chariot.It is one of the oldest temple owned by Gowda Saraswatha Community."</string>

<string name="chettikulangaradevitemple">"Chettikulangara Sree Bhagavathi temple is one of the most renowned temples in Kerala. The temple is located at Chettikulangara in Mavelikkara taluk of Alappuzha district in the south Indian state of Kerala. The temple is situated about 4 km west of Mavelikkara, 7 km north of Kayamkulam on SH6 (Kayamkulam - Thiruvalla Highway).
There are many popular beliefs related to the origin of Chettikulangara temple. The most popular one is as follows. Many centuries ago, some local chieftains went to witness the annual festivities at the Koypallikarazhma Bhagavathi temple situated a few kilometers from Chettikulangara. The visitors were humiliated and ridiculed by the Koypallikarazhma temple authorities and the village chieftains there. Perturbed by the humiliation, and out of retribution, they decided to construct a Bhagavathi temple at Chettikulangara. People of Chettikulangara united for this cause, and headed by the Karanavars (Family Heads) of the four to five then leading families of the region decided to seek the blessings of Kodungallur Bhagavathi in this mission. They embarked on a pilgrimage visiting various temples en route and reached Kodungallur, and performed 12 days long Bhajanam to please the Goddess. It is said that the Devi came in their dreams to say that she would soon come to Chettikulangara. Next day, they happily returned to Chettikulangara with a sacred sword given by the Velichappadu of Kodungallur temple, and started civil works of the temple.

A few days later, while the kadathukaran (local boatman) of the nearby Karippuzha rivulet was winding up his work on a late evening, he heard an old woman requesting his help to ferry her to the other shore. He felt it was his duty to help this lonely lady, and decided to accompany her to Chettikulangara, the destination she was said to be heading for. On the way, they took rest beneath a wayside tree (the place now houses the Puthusseriambalam temple), and the Kadathukaran brought food for them from a nearby[ mannan /washer man] house. Soon he fell asleep, and when he woke up by early daybreak, the lady had vanished. (It is said that this boatman was a Christian, and for helping Devi to ferry across the Karippuzha thodu, the descendents of his family were entrusted with the job of Vedi(ritual fireworks at the temple). He elaborated about this mysterious incident to the people of Chettikulangara, and they felt the Devi had reached Chettikulangara.

The next day, annual maintenance works on thatched roof was going on at the Illam(the traditional house where a community of Brahmins in central Kerala reside) adjacent to the present temple. While the Antharjanam of the house was serving the dishe of Kanji (Rice porridge) Muthirapuzhukku (a local special dish with ingredients of baked Horse Gram cereal and kneaded coconut) and Asthram (another side dish, a paste of different locally procured vegetables) for the workers, a strange old woman joined them for lunch. Soon after the food, the old lady moved to the western side of the house, and vanished in thin air with a bright glow. Antharjanam witnessed this, and she fell unconscious. Later she elaborated her experience to the people.

The same day, Devi showed her presence to the village chieftains. They approached famous astrologers, it was confirmed that the Bhagavathi had reached Chettikulangara."</string>

<string name="edakkalcaves">"Edakkal Caves (11°37'28.81?N 76°14'8.88?ECoordinates: 11°37'28.81?N 76°14'8.88?E) are two natural caves at a remote location at Edakkal, 25 km from Kalpetta in the Wayanad district of Kerala in India's Western Ghats. They lie 1,200 metres above sea level on Ambukutty Mala, beside an ancient trade route connecting the high mountains of Mysore to the ports of the Malabar coast. Inside the caves are pictorial writings believed to date to at least 6,000 BC,[1][2] from the Neolithic man, indicating the presence of a prehistoric civilization or settlement in this region.[3] The Stone Age carvings of Edakkal are rare and are the only known examples from south India.
These are not technically caves, but rather a cleft or rift approximately 96 feet (29 m) by 22 feet (6.7 m), a 30-foot-deep (9.1 m) fissure caused by a piece of rock splitting away from the main body. On one side of the cleft is a rock weighing several tons that covers the cleft to form the 'roof' of the cave. The carvings are of human and animal figures, tools used by humans and of symbols yet to be deciphered, suggesting the presence of a prehistoric settlement.[5]

The petroglyphs inside the cave are of at least three types. The oldest may date back to over 8,000 years. Evidences suggest that the Edakkal caves were inhabited several times at different points in history.

The caves were discovered by Fred Fawcett, a police official of the erstwhile Malabar state in 1890 who immediately recognised their anthropological and historical importance. He wrote an article about them, attracting the attention of scholars.The caves contain drawings that range over periods from as early as 5000 BC to 1000 BC. The youngest group of paintings have been in the news for a possible connection to the Indus Valley Civilization.
Historian M.R. Raghava Varier of the Kerala state archaeology department identified a sign “a man with jar cup” that is the most distinct motif of the Indus valley civilization.[11] The finding, made in September 2009, indicates that the Harappan civilization was active in the region. The “a man with jar cup” symbol from Edakkal seems to be more similar to the Indus motif than those already known from Tamil Nadu and Karnataka. Mr. Varier said “The discovery of the symbols are akin to that of the Harappan civilisation having predominantly Dravidian culture and testimony to the fact that cultural diffusion could take place. It is wrong to presume that the Indus culture disappeared into thin air.” Iravatham Mahadevan, a scholar of Indus valley and Brahmi scripts said the findings were very significant called it a "major discovery"."</string>

<string name="jawaharlalnehrustadium">"Jawaharlal Nehru International Stadium is a multipurpose international stadium situated in Kochi, Kerala. The stadium has a capacity of 60,500 spectators making it one of the largest stadiums in India. The stadium was built in 1996 by the Government of Kerala with Greater Cochin Development Authority (GCDA). The stadium is widely touted to be one of the most noisiest cricket stadium in the world due to its distinctive architecture.

Originally constructed as a football stadium, it has played host to a number of international cricket and football matches. The extensive grounds of the stadium serve as venue for important exhibitions, cinema events and political rallies in the city. The most innovative aspect of the stadium is its unique lighting towers of 2 kW Floodlights which when switched on fully can provide lighting levels for HD telecast. The Structure of the tower is itself one of a kind in India.[3][4] Greater Cochin Development Authority leased out the Jawaharlal Nehru International stadium at Kaloor to the Kerala Cricket Association (KCA) for a period of 30 years.

The stadium acts as the home ground for teams including Kerala cricket team, Kerala Blasters FC (Indian Super League).

Kochi is selected as one of the six host cities for 2017 FIFA U-17 World Cup to be held in India. This stadium will be the venue for matches in Kochi."</string>

<string name="thiruvananthapuramzoo">"The Thiruvananthapuram Zoo (also known as Trivandrum Zoo) is located in the city of Thiruvananthapuram, the capital of Kerala, India. It occupies 55 acres (22 ha) of woodland, lakes, and lawns. It is the oldest zoo in Asia.
Thiruvananthapuram Zoo is one of the oldest of its kind in India. Swathi Thirunal Rama Varma, who ruled Travancore between 1830 and 1847, established a menagerie where royal tigers, panthers, cheetahs, deer, boar, and other wild animals were kept. His brother Uthram Thirunal and British Resident William Cullen formally establish the Zoo in 1857 as an annex to the Napier Museum. The zoo was originally built with the typical iron-barred cages prevalent at the time, and was designed for recreational purposes, but with increased loss of forest and wildlife due to human development, the goal of the Zoo has changed from recreation to conservation.
The Thiruvananthapuram Zoo is home to 82 species from around the world. Indigenous species at the zoo include lion-tailed macaque, Nilgiri langur, Indian rhinoceros, Asiatic lion, royal Bengal tiger, White Tiger[4] and leopard,[2] as well a nine Asian elephants (as of March 31, 2009).[5] Animals from Africa include giraffes, hippos, zebras, and Cape buffalos.[2]

The zoo also includes a snake farm which exhibits both poisonous and non-poisonous snakes"</string>

<string name="veegaland">"Wonderla Holidays Limited is a leading amusement park designing and operating company in India headquartered near Bidadi, 28 kilometres (17 mi) from Bangalore. It is promoted by Kochouseph Chittilappilly and his son Arun Chittilappilly. Wonderla's flagship amusement park located at the same address is the second theme park project from the company and has been operational since October 2005. It is spread over an area of 82 acres (33 ha). The first amusement park, Wonderla Kochi, was set up in 2000. The parks have been set up with a total investment of over Rs. 2.5 billion.
Wonderla has 55 land and water-based rides.

The park features a wide variety of attractions including some rides, water rides, a musical fountain and laser shows, a virtual reality show. Wonderla Bangalore has a full-fledged dance floor with a twist: electronically controlled rain showers. Wonderla also has attractions specially designed for children, and these are gentle yet unusual like a kiddies free fall ride. It uses solar-heated water for all its pools during winter.

Wonderla has conference facilities for up to 1,000 persons, and features five restaurants with a total seating capacity of 1,150. It has locker rooms with over 2,350 lockers and restrooms and showers.[citation needed] The park also features a first aid facility and a paging system.

Wonderla opened its resort, an 84-room hotel complex spread over 100,000 square feet to public in 2012. The resort features dedicated children's play areas and other recreational and conferencing facilities.[1]

Wonderla, Bangalore has been ranked 1st in India and 7th best in Asia by Tripadvisor for 2014, the highest for any Amusement park in India."</string>

<string name="barodamuseumandpicturegallery">"The famous museum was built in 1894 on the lines of Victoria and Albert and Science Museums of London. Major Mant in association with R.F. Chisholm  who refined some of Mant's finest works to make genuine Indo-Saracenic architecture designed the Building of this Museum. It preserves a rich collection of art, sculpture, ethnography and ethnology. Several of the paintings are not only original but masterpieces at the picture gallery. The picture gallery which offers an excellent collection of originals by famous British painters Turner and constable and many others attract tourists from every part of the country. The Egyptian mummy and skeleton of a blue whale are major attractions for those who visit the museum. Other treasure includes the famous Akota bronzes dating the 5th Century AD, A collection of Mughal miniatures, a full-fledged gallery of Tibetan Art and oils by several European masters.

Maharaja Sayajirao Gaekwad III belonging to the Gaekwad dynasty of the Marathas founded the museum in 1887. The museum building was completed in 1894, when it opened to the public. Construction of the art gallery commenced in 1908, was completed in 1914, but did not open until 1921 as the First World War delayed transfer of pieces from Europe intended for the gallery."</string>

<string name="dwarkadishtemple">"The Dwarkadhish temple, also known as the Jagat Mandir and occasionally spelled "Dwarakadheesh", is a Hindu temple dedicated to Lord Krishna, who is worshipped here by the name Dwarkadhish, or 'King of Dwarka'. The main shrine of the 5-storied building, supported by 72 pillars, is known as Jagat Mandir or Nija Mandir, archaeological findings suggest it to be 2,200 - 2,000 years old.[1][2][3] Temple was enlarged in the 15th- 16th century.[4][5] The Dwarkadhish Temple is a Pushtimarg temple, hence it follows the guidelines and rituals created by Shree Vallabhacharya and Shree Vitheleshnathji.

According to tradition, the original temple was believed to have been built by Krishna's grandson, Vajranabha, over the hari-griha (Lord Krishna's residential place). The temple became part of the Char Dham pilgrimage considered sacred by Hindus in India, after Adi Shankaracharya, the 8th century Hindu theologian and philosopher, visited the shrine. The other three being comprising Rameswaram, Badrinath and Puri. Even today a memorial within the temple is dedicated to his visit. Dwarakadheesh is the 108th Divya Desam of Lord Vishnu on the subcontinent, glorified in the Divya Prabandha sacred texts."</string>

<string name="kashtabhanjanhanumanmandir">"Shri Hanuman Mandir, Sarangpur is a Hindu temple located in Sarangpur, Gujarat and comes under the Vadtal Gadi of the Swaminarayan Sampraday. It is dedicated to Hanuman in the form of Kastbhanjan (Crusher of sorrows).
This temple is among the more prominent ones in the Swaminarayan Sampraday. The image of Hanuman was installed by Sadguru Gopalanand Swami. According to author Raymond Williams, it is reported that when Sadguru Gopalanand Swami installed the image of Hanuman, he touched it with a rod and the image came alive and moved. This story has become a charter for the healing ritual performed at this temple.[1] The image of Hanuman here is a stout figure with a handlebar moustache, crushing a female demon under his foot and baring his teeth, standing among sculpted foliage full of fruit bearing monkey attendants.[2] In 1899, Kothari Gordhandas of Vadtal appointed Shastri Yagnapurushdas to manage the affairs of the mandir; during his tenure, Shastri Yagnapurushdas renovated the site, built the adjacent bungalow, and acquired more land for the complex to bring it to its current state.
The image of this temple is said to be so powerful that a mere look at it will drive the evil spirits out of the people affected by them.[4] Saturday is the designated day for a special ritual (as Saturday is dedicated to Hanuman) for those affected by mental illnesses and other disorders. They are brought to the temple to be touched by the rod used by Sadguru Gopalanand Swami during the installation ceremony of the image. This rod has now been covered in silver. The temple administration has hired a brahmin householder to act as a priest at the temple and conduct this ritual. After this, the person affected is instructed to circumambulate the shrine and repeat this after doing darshan a number of times. Some people take a special vow to do this a certain number of times or to chant the Swaminarayan Mahamantra while doing this."</string>

<string name="statueofunity">"The Statue of Unity is an under construction 182 metres (597 ft) monument of Vallabhbhai Patel that will be created directly facing the Narmada Dam, 3.2 km away on the river island called Sadhu Bet near Vadodara in Gujarat. This statue is planned to be spread over 20000 square meters of project area. It will also be surrounded by an artificial lake spread across 12 km of area. It would be the world's tallest statue. Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Rashtriya Ekta Trust (SVPRET), a special purpose vehicle was established by the Gujarat government and the outreach programme across India was carried out starting December 2013.
Initially the total cost of the project was estimated to be about ?2063 crore (US$320 million) by the government. Later Larsen and Toubro won the contract in October 2014 for its lowest bid of ?2989 crore (US$470 million) for the design, construction and maintenance. The construction was started on 31st October 2014."</string>

<string name="casinoroyalgoa">"INDIA'S LARGEST and MOST LUXURIOUS CASINO 40,000sq.ft of luxury gaming on three levels with 850 gaming positions.  Live entertainment including floorshows, bands, Stand-up-comedy and much more.  All the Games people play – Poker, Roulette, Indian Flush, Baccarat, Blackjack, Pontoon, Casino Wars, Sic Bo, Money Wheel, etc. World cuisine buffets and A-la-carte menus. The finest Single Malts, Wines and Live cooking stations.  The Grand Exclusive Whiskys lounge with its bar entertainment.  Above all L – 4: Gaming by Invitation.
The Casino is spread on 3 decks of the ship. It has about a 3k-5k entry with dummy chips. This comes with free food and liquor. It gets quite crowded in the weekends. The place is a good place to spend some time. In the dining area they have some entertainment going on."</string>

<string name="chaporabeach">"Chapora Beach is a coastal village at Chapora River estuary lying alongside a beach stretch in North Goa that is around 10 km. from Mapusa, a City in Northern Goa. It is close to Chapora Fort, an old Portuguese fort. Chapora is also close to a trawler-fishing jetty. Chapora is home to many cheapest travel accommodation houses found in entire Northern Goa. There is a famous Ganesh fruit juice center in Chapora selling organic juices and gathering people from around."</string>

<string name="dudhsagarfalls">"Dudhsagar Falls (literally Sea of Milk ) is a four-tiered waterfall located on the Mandovi River in the Indian state of Goa. It is 60 km from Panaji by road and is located on the Madgaon-Belgaum rail route about 46 km east of Madgaon and 80 km south of Belgaum. Dudhsagar Falls is amongst India's tallest waterfalls with a height of 310 m(1017 feet) and an average width of 30 metres (100 feet).
The falls is located in the Bhagwan Mahaveer Sanctuary and Mollem National Park amongst the Western ghats. The waterfall forms the border between Karnataka and Goa states. The area is surrounded by a deciduous forests with a rich bio diversity. The falls are not particularly spectacular during the dry season but during the monsoon season however, the falls are fed by rains and form a huge force of water.
The nearest rail station accessible by road to the falls is Castle Rock station. Visitors could get in a train from here and disembark at the Dudhsagar stop. It is to be noted that the Dudhsagar rail stop is not a station where passengers can expect a platform. Passengers and visitors have to climb down the steep ladder of the rail compartment in a short 1-2 minute unscheduled stop. From this rail stop, visitors have to walk about a kilometer on the tracks to arrive at the falls. While the walk itself is something unexpected for a popular tourist destination, there is a 200 m train tunnel that is totally dark which makes the walk a bit tougher. There is no availability of fresh drinking water nor clean rest room facilities anywhere in the vicinity of the falls including at the rail stop. There is absolutely no access to power or cellular signal at this location just as there is no access to road transportation. Caution needs to be exercised when planning a trip to the falls with elders or children. There are many outdoor adventure organizations that organize monsoon treks to Dudhsagar for people interested in adventures that includes trekking from Castle Rock and camping under the falls for a night."</string>

<string name="goastatemuseum">"Goa State Museum is located in Panjim, which is the capital city of Goa. This new museum complex, located in the EDC Complex in Patto, was inaugurated by the President of India on June 18th, 1996. Prior to this date, artifacts was set up in the Department of Archives in Goa by the Archeology and Museum unit. Thereafter, a small museum was opened to the public on September 29th, 1977 in a rented building at St. Inez, also in Panjim.

The museum currently has around 8,000 artifacts on display, which include stone sculptures, wooden objects, carvings, bronzes, paintings, manuscripts, rare coins, numismatic collection, and anthropological objects. It is well known among other museums for its collection of Hindu and Jain artifacts and sculptures."</string>

<string name="chherapunji">"Cherrapunji currently the historical name Sohra is more commonly used; alternative spellings are Cherrapunjee and Charrapunji), is a subdivisional town in the East Khasi Hills district in the Indian state of Meghalaya. It is credited as being the wettest place on Earth, although nearby Mawsynram currently holds that record. Cherrapunji still holds the all-time record for the most rainfall in a calendar month and in a year: it received 9,300 mm (366 in) in July 1861 and 26,461 mm (1,041.75 in) between 1 August 1860 and 31 July 1861.[1]

Cherrapunji is the traditional capital of a hima (Khasi tribal chieftainship constituting a petty state) known as Sohra or Churra.
The original name for this town was Sohra, which was pronounced "Churra" by the British. This name eventually evolved into the current name, Cherrapunji. The name "cherrapunji" which means 'land of oranges' was first used by tourists from other parts of India. Despite perennial rainfall, Cherrapunji faces an acute water shortage and the inhabitants often have to trek for miles to obtain potable water.[2] Irrigation is also hampered due to excessive rain washing away the topsoil as a result of human encroachment into the forests. The Meghalaya state government has renamed Cherrapunjee back to its original name, "Sohra". There is a monument to David Scott (British Administrator in NE India, 1802–31) in the Cherrapunji cemetery. The history of the Khasis – the inhabitants of Cherrapunji – may be traced from the early part of the 16th century. Between the 16th and 18th centuries these people were ruled by the 'Syiems (rajas or chiefs) of Khyriem' in the Khasi hills. The Khasi hills came under British authority in 1883 with the submission of the last of the important syiems, Tirot Singh.

The main pivot on which the entire superstructure of Khasi society rests is the matrilineal system."</string>
<string name="dawki">"Dawki-Tamabil is one of the few road border crossings between India and Bangladesh. It is used mainly for coal transportation to Bangladesh. Some 500 trucks cross the border every day in peak season.

Some shared transport is available from Barabazar in Shillong to the border post at Dawki every morning. Buses are also available for the 70 kilometres (43 mi) journey from Shillong. On the other side inside Bangladesh the Tamabil bus station, 1.5 kilometres (0.93 mi) away, has regular bus service to Sylhet 55 kilometres (34 mi) away."</string>
<string name="mawsynram">"Mawsynram is a village in the East Khasi Hills district of Meghalaya state in north-eastern India, 65 kilometres from Shillong. It is reportedly the wettest place on Earth, with an average annual rainfall of 11,872 millimetres (467.4 in), but that claim is disputed by Lloró, Colombia, which reported an average yearly rainfall of 12,717 millimetres (500.7 in) between 1952 and 1989 and López de Micay, also in Colombia, which reported 12,892 mm (507.6 in) per year between 1960 and 2012.According to the Guinness Book of World Records, Mawsynram received 26,000 millimetres (1,000 in) of rainfall in 1985.


Under the Köppen climate classification, Mawsynram features a subtropical highland climate with an extraordinarily rainy and lengthy monsoonal season. Based on the data of a recent few decades, it appears to be the wettest place in the world, or the place with the highest average annual rainfall. Mawsynram receives nearly 10 metres of rain in an average year, and the vast majority of it falls during the monsoon months. A comparison of rainfalls for Cherrapunji and Mawsynram for some years is given in Table 1.[10]

Primarily due to the high altitude, it seldom gets truly hot in Mawsynram. Average monthly temperatures range from around 11 degrees Celsius in January to just above 20 degrees Celsius in August. The village also experiences a brief but noticeably drier season from December until February, when monthly precipitation on average does not exceed 30 millimetres (1.2 in). The little precipitation during the village’s “low sun” season is something that is shared by many areas with this type of climate.

Table 1: Comparison of rainfalls for Cherrapunji and Mawsynram for some years."</string>
<string name="shillong">"Shillong is the capital and hill station of Meghalaya, also known as "The Abode of Clouds", one of the smallest states in India. It is the headquarters of the East Khasi Hills district and is situated at an average altitude of 4,908 feet (1,496 m) above sea level, with the highest point being Shillong Peak at 6,449 feet (1,966 m). Shillong is the 330th most populous city in India with population of 143,007 according to the 2011 census.[4] It is said that the rolling hills around the town reminded the European settlers of Scotland. Hence, they would also refer to it as the "Scotland of the East". The population density of the state of Meghalaya in the 2000s was 342 people per sq mile.

It has steadily grown in size and significance since it was made the civil station of the Khasi and Jaintia Hills in 1864 by the British. In 1874, on the formation of Assam as the Chief Commissioners Province, it was chosen as the headquarters of the new administration because of its convenient location between the Brahmaputra and Surma valleys and more so because the climate of Shillong was much cooler than tropical India. Shillong remained the capital of undivided Assam until the creation of the new state of Meghalaya on 21 January 1972, when Shillong became the capital of Meghalaya, and Assam moved its capital to Dispur in Guwahati. Shillong is also often called as "Indias Rock Capital" due to its inhabitants great passion for music.

Shillong is at  WikiMiniAtlas25.57°N 91.88°E. It is on the Shillong Plateau, the only major uplifted structure in the northern Indian shield.[6] The city lies in the centre of the plateau and is surrounded by hills, three of which are revered in Khasi tradition: Lum Sohpetbneng, Lum Diengiei and Lum Shillong.

Weather conditions: Pleasant, pollution-free; summers: The temperature varies from 23 °C (73 °F); winters: The temperature varies from 4 °C (39 °F).
Location: Shillong, the capital city of Meghalaya is just 131.5 km (81.7 mi) from Guwahati which can be accessed by road along NH 40 , a journey of about 2 hours 30 minutes through lush green hills and the magnificent Umiam lake in between."</string>
<string name="umiumlake">"Umiam Lake is a reservoir located in the hills 15 km to the North of Shillong in the state of Meghalaya, India. It was created by damming the Umiam river in the early 1960s. The principal catchment area of the lake and dam is spread over 220 square km.
The lake was formed as part of building a Dam. The dam started construction in 1965. The dam has the distinction of being the first Hydel power project in the North-east region of India.
The lake serves as a major tourist attraction for the state of Meghalaya. It is also a popular destination for water sport and adventure facilities. Tourists visit this spot for kayaking, water cycling, scooting and boating.Apart from storing water for electricity generation, the lake also provides numerous ecosystem services at micro, meso and macro levels. Downstream irrigation, fisheries and drinking water cater to local anthropogenic needs.
Due to the rising population of Shillong which is situated upstream of the lake, the lake is starting to become highly polluted. Also, there is the heavy problem of silting. An estimated 40,000 cubic metres of silt enter Umiam Lake every year. Causes range between upstream encroachments, deforestation, blockage of natural drainage systems and unscientific mining et al. in the catchment area. Excessive silt load in the lake has lowered the storage."</string>
<string name="ganeshtok">"Close to Tashi View point is Ganesh Tok, a temple of Lord Gansha. It's located at an altitude of 6,500 ft and at a hill adjacent to that of the huge TV Tower. Like Hanuman Tok, tourists come here not only to offer prayers to Ganesh, but also to soak in the views from the viewing lounge and the circular balcony around it. 
 
You will need to climb a stair case to reach to the upper levels where the temple and viewing area are located. Mid-away along the staircase you will be required to take off your shoes. The temple itself is quite small. However next to is the enclosed viewing lounge with glass panels. The balcony around is even better for the views. You can see the Gangtok town, rolling hill and the snow capped mountains including Kanchenjunga. 
There is gift and souvenir shop in the complex. Down stairs a few steps away is a cafe serving tea, coffee and various snack items like toast and omelet, veg momos, noodles, paratthas, cold drinks, bottled water etc at reasonable price. Ask them to put less sugar in tea or else they are very generous in making the tea sweeter than what you may like. But that I guess is the case in whole of Gangtok. While veg momos are nice and served with sauce, I like the toast a omelet here. They sandwich the omelet in toast, cut them into triangular pieces and serve with ketchup. 
There is no admission fee at Ganesh Tok, however donations aer welcome. Just next to Ganesh Tok is the Pinetum garden. Take a stroll through the pine trees and enjoy the ambience. 
Ganesh tok is only 6kms from Gangtok Town. The standard local tours offered by the taxi drivers cover this as part of sightseeing. You can otherwise just hire a taxi and come here. Opposite to Ganesh Tok is the entrance to the Zoo. "</string>
<string name="hanumantok">"Hanuman Tok is a Hindu temple complex which is located in upper reaches of Gangtok, the capital of Indian state of Sikkim. The temple is dedicated to lord Hanuman, the Monkey God. The temple is maintained by the Indian army.
According to the local legends, when Hanuman was flying with the “Sanjeevani”( mythological life saving herb) mountain to save Rama's brother Lakshmana he rested in the spot where his temple now lies for some time. The mandir is actually managed by The Indian Army."</string>
<string name="nathulapass">"Nathu La is a mountain pass in the Himalayas. It connects the Indian state of Sikkim with China's Tibet Autonomous Region. The pass, at 4,310 m (14,140 ft) above mean sea level,[1] forms a part of an offshoot of the ancient Silk Road. Nathu means "listening ears" and La means "pass" in Tibetan. On the Indian side, the pass is 54 km (34 mi) east of Gangtok, the capital of Indian state of Sikkim. Only citizens of India can visit the pass, and then only after obtaining a permit in Gangtok.

Nathu La is one of the second open trading border posts between China and India; the next is Shipkila in Himachal Pradesh and Lipulekh (or Lipulech) in Nepal is also an other way.[3] Sealed by India after the 1962 Sino-Indian War, Nathu La was re-opened in 2006 following numerous bilateral trade agreements. The opening of the pass was expected to bolster the economy of the region and play a key role in the growing Sino-Indian trade, but that has not happened. Currently, agreements between the two nations limit trade across the pass to 29 types of goods from India and 15 from the Chinese side. The opening, however, shortens the travel distance to important Hindu and Buddhist pilgrimage sites in the region.


Distant mountains of Bhutan, the Tibetan side, and international border fence as seen from the Indian side at Nathu La.
It is also one of the four officially agreed BPM (Border Personnel Meeting) points between the Indian Army and People's Liberation Army of China for regular consultations and interactions between the two armies, which helps in defusing face-offs. The four BPM are: Chushul in Ladakh, Nathu La in Sikkim, Bum La Pass in Tawang district of Arunachal Pradesh, and Lipulekh Pass in Uttarakhand close to Qiang."</string>
<string name="rumtekmonastery">"Rumtek Monastery also called the Dharmachakra Centre, is a gompa located in the Indian state of Sikkim near the capital Gangtok. It is a focal point for the sectarian tensions within the Karma Kagyu school of Tibetan Buddhism that characterize the Karmapa controversy.
Originally built under the direction of Changchub Dorje, 12th Karmapa Lama in the mid-1700s, Rumtek served as the main seat of the Karma Kagyu lineage in Sikkim for some time. But when Rangjung Rigpe Dorje, 16th Karmapa, arrived in Sikkim in 1959 after fleeing Tibet, the monastery was in ruins. Despite being offered other sites, the Karmapa decided to rebuild Rumtek. To him, the site possessed many auspicious qualities and was surrounded by the most favorable attributes. For example, flowing streams, mountains behind, a snow range in front, and a river below. With the generosity and help of the Sikkim royal family and the local folks of Sikkim, it was built by the 16th Karmapa as his main seat in exile.

After four years, construction of the monastery was completed. The sacred items and relics brought out from Tsurphu Monastery, the Karmapa's seat in Tibet, were installed. On Losar in 1966, the 16th Karmapa officially inaugurated the new seat, called "The Dharmachakra Centre, a place of erudition and spiritual accomplishment, the seat of the glorious Karmapa."[citation needed]

The monastery is currently the largest in Sikkim. It is home to the community of monks and where they perform the rituals and practices of the Karma Kagyu lineage. A golden stupa contains the relics of the 16th Karmapa. Opposite that building is a college, Karma Shri Nalanda Institute for Higher Buddhist Studies.

Rumtek is located 24 kilometres (15 mi) from Gangtok, the capital of Sikkim, at an altitude of about 1,500 metres (4,900 ft).

The Rumtek Monastery features in the 2014 Indian mystery thriller novel The emperor's riddles by Satyarth Nayak."</string>
<string name="gurudongmarlake">"Nathu La is a mountain pass in the Himalayas. It connects the Indian state of Sikkim with China's Tibet Autonomous Region. The pass, at 4,310 m (14,140 ft) above mean sea level,[1] forms a part of an offshoot of the ancient Silk Road. Nathu means "listening ears" and La means "pass" in Tibetan. On the Indian side, the pass is 54 km (34 mi) east of Gangtok, the capital of Indian state of Sikkim. Only citizens of India can visit the pass, and then only after obtaining a permit in Gangtok.

Nathu La is one of the second open trading border posts between China and India; the next is Shipkila in Himachal Pradesh and Lipulekh (or Lipulech) in Nepal is also an other way.[3] Sealed by India after the 1962 Sino-Indian War, Nathu La was re-opened in 2006 following numerous bilateral trade agreements. The opening of the pass was expected to bolster the economy of the region and play a key role in the growing Sino-Indian trade, but that has not happened. Currently, agreements between the two nations limit trade across the pass to 29 types of goods from India and 15 from the Chinese side. The opening, however, shortens the travel distance to important Hindu and Buddhist pilgrimage sites in the region.


Distant mountains of Bhutan, the Tibetan side, and international border fence as seen from the Indian side at Nathu La.
It is also one of the four officially agreed BPM (Border Personnel Meeting) points between the Indian Army and People's Liberation Army of China for regular consultations and interactions between the two armies, which helps in defusing face-offs. The four BPM are: Chushul in Ladakh, Nathu La in Sikkim, Bum La Pass in Tawang district of Arunachal Pradesh, and Lipulekh Pass in Uttarakhand close to Qiang."</string>
<string name="assamstatemuseum">"The Assam State Museum is located in the southern end of Dighali Pukhuri tank which is in the heart of Guwahati city, Assam. The Museum was established by the Kamarupa Anusandhan Samiti (Assam Research Society) in 1940.[1] Late Kanklal Baruah was founder president. In the year 1953, it was taken over by the State Govt.
Assam State Museum surpasses all the other museums in India, as one of the biggest multipurpose museum. The exhibits of the Museum are displayed under different sections, viz., Epigraphy, Sculptures-The sculptures from the Assam region fall into four principal categories - stone, wood, metal and terracotta, Miscellaneous, Natural History, Crafts, Anthropology and Folk Art and Arms section. The collections which are on display here, are very rare.

The library in Assam State Museum was established in 1985, is rich in its stenographic collections. There are various periodicals, journals and books relating to art, culture, mythology, biography, encyclopedic works and even the Asiatic Society journals of the country."</string>
<string name="kamakhyatemple">"The Kamakhya Temple also Kamrup-Kamakhya is a Hindu temple dedicated to the mother goddess Kamakhya. It is one of the oldest of the 51 Shakti Pithas. Situated on the Nilachal Hill in western part of Guwahati city in Assam, India, it is the main temple in a complex of individual temples dedicated to the ten Mahavidyas: Kali, Tara, Sodashi, Bhuvaneshwari, Bhairavi, Chhinnamasta, Dhumavati, Bagalamukhi, Matangi and Kamala. Among these, Tripurasundari, Matangi and Kamala reside inside the main temple whereas the other seven reside in individual temples.[6] It is an important pilgrimage destination for general Hindu and especially for Tantric worshipers.

In July 2015, the Supreme Court of India transferred the administration of the Temple from the Kamakhya Debutter Board to the Bordeuri Samaj.
The current structural temple, built and renovated many times in the period 8th-17th century, gave rise to a hybrid indigenous style that is sometimes called the Nilachal type: a temple with a hemispherical dome on a cruciform base.[8] The temple consists of four chambers: garbhagriha and three mandapas locally called calanta, pancharatna and natamandira aligned from east to west."</string>
<string name="kaziranganationalpark">"Kaziranga National Park is a national park in the Golaghat and Nagaon districts of the state of Assam, India. A World Heritage Site, the park hosts two-thirds of the world's great one-horned rhinoceroses.[1] According to the latest census held in March, 2015, the current Rhino population in Kaziranga National Park is 2401 as published by the Forest Department under Govt. of Assam, an operation conducted by the department officials in association with some recognized wildlife NGOs. The 2015 census revealed rhino population as 1,651 adults (663 males, 802 females, 186 unsexed), 294 sub-adults (90 males, 114 females, 90 unsexed), 251 juveniles and 205 cubs. [2] Kaziranga boasts the highest density of tigers among protected areas in the world and was declared a Tiger Reserve in 2006. The park is home to large breeding populations of elephants, wild water buffalo, and swamp deer.[3] Kaziranga is recognized as an Important Bird Area by Birdlife International for conservation of avifaunal species. Compared to other protected areas in India, Kaziranga has achieved notable success in wildlife conservation. Located on the edge of the Eastern Himalaya biodiversity hotspot, the park combines high species diversity and visibility.

Kaziranga is a vast expanse of tall elephant grass, marshland, and dense tropical moist broadleaf forests, crisscrossed by four major rivers, including the Brahmaputra, and the park includes numerous small bodies of water. Kaziranga has been the theme of several books, songs, and documentaries. The park celebrated its centennial in 2005 after its establishment in 1905 as a reserve forest."</string>
<string name="umanandatemple">"Umananda Devaloi  is a Shiva temple located at the Peacock Island in the middle of river Brahmaputra just opposite the office of the Deputy Commissioner of Kamrup or the Kachari Ghat in Guwahati. It was built by the Ahom King Gadadhar Singha (1681–1696), who was a devout Shaivaite.

It is known as smallest inhabited riverine island in the world. Country boats that are available on the bank of Brahmaputra take the visitors to the island. The mountain on which the temple has been built is known as Bhasmacala.
Siva is said to have resided here in the form of Bhayananda. According to the Kalika Purana, in the beginning of the creation Siva sprinkled ashes (bhasma) at this place and imparted knowledge to Parvati (his consort). It is said that, when Siva was in meditation on this hillock, Kamadeva interrupted his yoga and was therefore burnt to ashes by the fire of Siva’s anger and hence the hillock got the name Bhasmacala.

This mountain is also called Bhasmakuta. The Kalika Purana states that Urvasikunda is situated here and here resides the goddess Urvasi who brings Amrit (nectar) for the enjoyment of Kamakhya and hence the island got the name Urvasi Island."</string>
<string name="imphalcity">"The city of Imphal is the capital of the Indian state of Manipur. The ruins of the Palace of Kangla, the royal seat of the erstwhile Kingdom of Manipur, are in the city centre, surrounded by a moat.
Originally ruled by King Khaba, the throne of Imphal was later ceded by the Pakhangba leaders. It was here that the Ningthouja dynasty originated. The Ningthouja people expanded their influence in politics and warfare. The Kangla Palace, built by King Khagemba and his son Khunjaoba, was destroyed by the British during the Anglo-Manipuri War. During the reign of Maharaja Bhagyachandra, the region experienced several Burmese invasions; however, with the help of Gambhir Singh and the Manipur army, Kangla was liberated from the Burmese forces.
The region remained peaceful until British officials arrived in 1891. Taking advantage of internal differences among the royal family, the British sent J. W. Quinton to negotiate. The situation worsened; Senapati Tikendrajit was banished from the capital, which led to the first Anglo-Manipur war. Britain's undeclared rule over Manipur angered the local population. In 1892, the second Anglo-Manipur war broke out between the British and forces led by the Manipuri commander-in-chief. The British attacked the palace, and gunned down the walls of Kangal Fort. After its capture, Manipur remained a part of British India until independence in 1947. Imphal was the scene of the Battle of Imphal .
    "</string>
<string name="keibullamjaonationalpark">"The Keibul Lamjao National Park is a national park in the Bishnupur district of the state of Manipur in India. It is 40 km2 (15.4 sq mi) in area, the only floating park in the world, located in North East India, and an integral part of Loktak Lake.

The national park is characterized by many floating decomposed plant materials locally called phumdis. To preserve the natural refuge of the endangered Manipur Eld's deer or brow-antlered deer (Cervus eldi eldi), or sangai also called the dancing deer, listed as an endangered species by IUCN, the park which was initially declared to be a sanctuary in 1966, was subsequently declared to be a national park in 1977 through a gazette notification. The act has generated local support and public awareness.
The brow-antlered deer, which was first discovered in Manipur in 1839 and named Cervus eldi eldi in 1844 in honour of Lt. Percy Eld – a British officer, was reported an extinct species in 1951. It was re–discovered in the Keibul Lamjao Park area by the environmentalist and photographer E.P.Gee, which necessitated declaring this reserve park area as a national park to protect and conserve the deer now called Eld's deer's subspecies brow-antlered deer (Cervus eldi eldi) or sangai in Manipuri language (to distinguish it from the other two sub species found in Burma and Thailand that are called Cervus eldii thamin and Cervus eldii siamensis and also in Cambodia, China, Laos, Thailand, Vietnam and Hianan island). It has a pride of place in the folklore and culture of the Manipur state and is the state animal of Manipur. From a small herd of 14 deer in 1975, its population was reportedly 155 in 1995."</string>
<string name="loktaklake">"Loktak Lake is the largest freshwater lake in North -East India is famous for the phumdis (heterogeneous mass of vegetation, soil, and organic matters at various stages of decomposition) floating over it. Keibul Lamjao the only floating national park in the world floats over it.It is located near Moirang in Manipur state, India.[1] The etymology of Loktak is Lok = "stream" and tak = "the end".[2] The Keibul Lamjao National Park, which is the last natural refuge of the endangered sangai or Manipur brow-antlered deer (Cervus eldi eldi), one of three subspecies of Eld's deer, covering an area of 40 km2 (15 sq mi), is situated in the southeastern shores of this lake and is the largest of all the phumdis in the lake.

This ancient lake plays an important role in the economy of Manipur. It serves as a source of water for hydropower generation, irrigation and drinking water supply. The lake is also a source of livelihood for the rural fisherman who live in the surrounding areas and on phumdis, also known as “phumshongs”. Human activity has led to severe pressure on the lake ecosystem. 55 rural and urban hamlets around the lake have a population of about 100,000 people.[3][4][5][6] Considering the ecological status and its biodiversity values, the lake was initially designated as a wetland of international importance under the Ramsar Convention on 23 March 1990.[1] It was also listed under the Montreux Record on 16 June 1993, "a record of Ramsar sites where changes in ecological character have occurred, are occurring or are likely to occur"."</string>
<string name="badrinathtemple">"Badrinath Temple, also called Badrinarayan Temple, is a Hindu temple dedicated to Vishnu which is situated in the town of Badrinath in Uttarakhand, India. The temple and town form one of the four Char Dham and Chota Char Dham pilgrimage sites. The temple is also one of the 108 Divya Desams dedicated to Vishnu, who is worshipped as Badrinath—holy shrines for Vaishnavites. It is open for six months every year, between the end of April and the beginning of November, because of extreme weather conditions in the Himalayan region. The temple is located in Garhwal hill tracks in Chamoli district along the banks of Alaknanda River at an elevation of 3,133 m (10,279 ft) above the mean sea level. It is one of the most visited pilgrimage centres of India, having recorded 1,060,000 visits.

The image of the presiding deity worshipped in the temple is a 1 m (3.3 ft) tall, black stone statue of Vishnu in the form of Badrinarayan. The statue is considered by many Hindus to be one of eight swayam vyakta kshetras, or self-manifested statues of Vishnu.
Mata Murti Ka Mela, which commemorates the descent of river Ganges on mother earth, is the most prominent festival celebrated in the Badrinath Temple. Although Badrinath is located in North India, the head priest, or Rawal, is traditionally a Nambudiri Brahmin chosen from the South Indian state of Kerala. The temple was included in the Uttar Pradesh state government Act No. 30/1948 as Act no. 16,1939, which later came to be known as Shri Badarinath and Shri Kedarnath Mandir Act. The committee nominated by the state government administers both the temples and has seventeen members on its board."</string>
<string name="harkipauri">"Jai Ganga Maa Har Ki Pauri is a famous ghat on the banks of the Ganges in Haridwar in Uttarakhand state in India. This revered place is the major landmark of the holy city of Haridwar. Literally, "Har" means "Lord Shiva" who is the god according to shaivite Rishav school of Hindu theology, "Ki" means "of" and "Pauri" means "steps". Lord Shiva and Lord Vishnu are believed to have visited the Brahmakund in Har Ki Pauri in the Vedic times. There is a large footprint said to belong to Lord Vishnu on a stone wall.

It is believed that it is precise spot where the Ganges leaves the mountains and enters the plains. The ghat is on the west bank of Ganges canal through which the Ganges is diverted just to the north. Har Ki Pauri is also the area where thousands of pilgrims converge and the festivities commence during the Kumbha Mela, which takes place every twelve years, and the Ardh Kumbh Mela, which takes place every six years and the Punjabi festival of Vaisakhi, a harvest festival occurring every year in the month of April .
King Vikramaditya is said to have built it in 1st century BC in the memory of his brother, Bharthari who had come to meditate here on the bank of the Ganges. An area within Har Ki Pauri, where the evening Ganga Aarti takes places and which is considered most sacred is known as Brahmakund. It is considered to be the spot where the drops of Amrit fell over from the sky, while being carried in a pitcher by the celestial bird, Garuda after the Samudra Manthan.

Every day, Har Ki Pauri ghat witnesses hundreds taking a dip in water of the Ganges. The place is considered very auspicious. Over the years the ghats have undergone major extension and renovation as the crowds increased in subsequent Kumbh Melas. Several temples have come up on the steps, most built in late 19th century."</string>
<string name="hemkundsahib">"Hemkund Sahib (also spelled Hemkunt), known as Gurudwara Sri Hemkunt Sahib Ji, is a Sikh place of worship and pilgrimage site in Chamoli district, Uttarakhand, India. It is devoted to Guru Gobind Singh Ji (1666–1708), the tenth Sikh Guru, and finds mention in Dasam Granth, a work believed to be dictated by Guruji himself. With its setting of a glacial lake surrounded by seven mountain peaks, each adorned by a Nishan Sahib on its cliff, it is according to the Survey of India located in the Himalayas at an elevation of 4,632 meters (15,197 feet).[1] It is approached from Gobindghat on the Rishikesh-Badrinath highway. The main town near Gobindghat is Joshimath.
Hemkunt is a Sanskrit name derived from Hem ("Snow") and Kund ("bowl"). Dasam Granth says this is the place where Pandu Raja practiced Yoga. In addition, the Dasam Granth says God ordered Sikh Guru Gobind Singh to take birth while he was in deep meditation at the mount of Hemkunt.Hemkund is inaccessible from October through April because of snow bound paths and glaciers. Sikh pilgrims arrive in May and set to work to repair the damage to the path over the winter, which tradition is called kar seva ("work service"), a concept which forms an important tenet of the Sikh faith.

The take-off point for Hemkund Sahib is the town of Govindghat about 275 kilometres (171 mi) from Rishikesh. The 13 kilometres (8.1 mi) trek is along a reasonably well maintained path to the village of Ghangaria (also called Govinddham). This path can be covered either by walk or by pony and a Gurudwara here gives shelter to pilgrims. In addition there are a few hotels and a camp ground with tents and mattresses. A 1,100-metre (3,600 ft)climb on a 6-kilometre (3.7 mi) of stone paved path leads Hemkund. Overnight stay is not allowed at Hemkund Sahib and so it is necessary to leave by 2 PM to make it back to Govindghat by nightfall.

From Delhi, tourists take the train to Haridwar and then travel by bus to Govindghat via Rishikesh. It is also possible to drive from Delhi to Govindghat, a distance of about 500 kilometres (310 mi) which takes around 18 hours to cover. Recently, an Indian airline company has started a helicopter service between Govindghat and Ghangria. The flight takes about 5 minutes."</string>
<string name="nainitallake">"Nainital Lake, a natural freshwater body, situated amidst the township of Nainital in Uttarakhand State of India, tectonic in origin, is kidney shaped or crescent shaped and has an outfall at the southeastern end.
Nainital Lake, in the Nainital district called the Lake District of India, is one of the four Lakes of Kumaon hills; the other three lakes are the Sattal Lake, the Bhimtal Lake and the Naukuchiyatal Lake.Historical records confirm that in 1839, Mr. P. Barron, from Rosa, an English business man in sugar trade, on a hunting expedition accidentally coming across the lake at Nainital was so captivated that he decided to build a European Colony on shores of the lake. The news magazine, the Englishman Calcutta, reported in 1841 discovery of this lake near Almora.
The lake is bounded by the high and steep Naina peak on the North West side, by the Tiffin Top to the south west side and snow view peaks on the north. Coniferous forest trees cover these hill ranges. The annual rainfall in the basin area of the lake is reported to be 1294.5 mm (43.15 inches). Tropical monsoon climate with maximum temperature 24.6 °C and minimum of 0.5 °C are recorded. The water is reported to be alkaline in nature (ph value of 8.4–9.3).
The lake receives flows from the surrounding catchment basin which comprises the hill slopes and springs. The hydrologic studies related to water balance and sedimentation was done using radioisotopes for estimating/measuring the various components of the inflow and outflow into the lake. Studies indicated that the subsurface inflow and outflow were significant – ranging from 43 to 63percent and 41 to 54 percent, respectively, of the total inflow and outflow, except in years of exceptionally heavy rainfall. The components of outflows were the surface outflow, the subsurface outflow through the springs on the downstream side and draft through wells for meeting the water supply of Nainital town and evaporation loss from the lake surface. The mean water retention time for the lake was computed as 1.16 years for the mean annual rainfall."</string>
<string name="neelkanthmahadevtemple">"Neelkanth Mahadev Temple is a Hindu temple dedicated to Nilkanth (Lord Shiva). The temple is situated at a height of 1330 meters and is located about 32 km from Rishikesh in the Pauri Garhwal district of Uttarakhand, India.

The temple is one of the most revered holy shrines dedicated to Lord Shiva and is a prominent Hindu pilgrimage site. It is surrounded by dense forests and is adjacent to the mountain ranges of Nar-Narayan. It is enveloped between the valleys of Manikoot, Brahmakoot and Vishnukoot and is located at the confluence of the rivers Pankaja and Madhumati.
According to Hindu mythology, the place where the Neelkanth Mahadev Temple currently stands is the sacred location where Lord Shiva consumed the poison Halahala that originated from the sea when Devas (Gods) and Asuras (Demons) churned the ocean in order to obtain Amrita. This poison that emanated during the Samudramanthan (churning of ocean) made his throat blue in color. Thus, Lord Shiva is also known as Nilkanth, literally meaning The Blue Throated One.
The sikhara of the temple is adorned with sculptures of various Devas and Asuras depicting the Samudramanthan. Neelkanth Mahadev in the form of Shivalinga is the presiding deity of the temple. The temple complex also has a natural spring where devotees usually take a holy bath before entering the premises of surrounded by dense forests."</string>
<string name="ramjhula">"Ram Jhula  is an iron suspension bridge situated at Muni Ki Reti in Rishikesh in Indian state of Uttarakhand. Built in the 1986, over river Ganges to cross the river and is a landmark of Rishikesh.

Ram jhula is located 3 kilometres (1.9 mi) north of Rishikesh at Muni Ki Reti. There are some of the Hindu ashrams and religious centers like "Gita Bhawan", and "Swargashram" located here.[1] It is also a connecting bridge between Swargashram, Gita Bhawan and other temples with Sivananda Ashram. Though similar in design, this bridge is bigger than Lakshman Jhula This bridge constructed with the span of 750 feet (230 m)."</string>

<string name="bhoramdeotemple">"Bhoramdeo Templeis a complex of Hindu temples dedicated to the god Shiva in Bhoramdeo, in the Indian state of Chhattisgarh.[1] It comprises a group of four temples of which the earliest is a brick-temple.[2]

The main temple is the Bhoramdeo temple built in stone.The architectural features with erotic sculptures has given a distinct style akin to the Khajuraho temple and the Konarak Sun Temple in Odisha, and hence the Bhoramdeo complex is known by the sobriquet the "Khajuraho of Chhattisgarh".

Another temple within a distance of about 1 kilometre (0.62 mi) from Bhoramdeo, which is mentioned along with the Bhoramdeo complex is the Madwa Mahal, meaning marriage hall in local dialect, also known as Dullhadeo. It was built in 1349 during the reign of Ramchandra Deo of the Nagavanshi dynasty and has a unique Shiva Linga erected over 16 pillars.
The Bhoramdeao temple complex is built at the foot of the thickly forested scenic backdrop of the Maikal range of hills,[3] in the Daksina Kosala region, which is in the present day Indian state of Chhattisgarh which was earlier part of Madhya Pradesh. It is situated 18 km to the North-West of the tehsil town of Kawardha in Kabirdham district.
The nearest airport to the Bhoramdeo complex is 134 km away near Raipur, which is the capital of Chattisgarh and Taipur is well coneected with the many major cities of the country. Raipur is also the nearest railhead Bombay-Howarah main line. Road communications from Kawardha, the nearest tehsil town to the temple complex, exists to Raipur (116 km), Rajnandgaon(133 km) and Jabalpur(220 km)."</string>
<string name="chitrakotwaterfall">"The Chitrakote Falls is a natural waterfall located to the west of Jagdalpur, in Bastar district in the Indian state of Chhattisgarh on the Indravati River. The height of the falls is about 29 metres (95 ft).[1][2] It is the widest fall in India,[3] Because of its width and wide spread during the monsoon season, it is often called the Niagara Falls of India.
The Chitrakote Falls is located on the Indravati River. The river originates in the kalahandi region of Orissa, in the Vindhya Range of hills, flows westward and then forms a fall at Chitrakote, enters Andhra Pradesh and finally flows into the Godavari River,[5] after traversing 240 miles (390 km) in the state, at Bhadrakali.[6][7] The free drop of the falls is a sheer height of about 30 metres (98 ft). It is located at a distance of 38 kilometres (24 mi) to the west of Jagadlpur. Because of its horseshoe shape, it is compared with the Niagara Falls and is given the sobriquet ‘the Small Niagara Falls’. During the rainy season, from July and October, rainbows are created with sun rays reflecting on mist from the waterfall.[8]

On the left bank of the Chitakoot Falls, a small Hindu shrine dedicated to the god Shiva and several naturally created grottos named "Parvati caves" (named after Shiva's wife Parvati) are located. The weather in the area is generally pleasant except in the summer season when it is hot due to absence of vegetation in the area.[9] The river flows sluggishly on the upstream side of the falls due to its meandering nature as it drains through the plains of Jagadalpur. This reach of the river valley has very little forest cover. Below the falls the river traverses the Bodhghat forested area and the river regime undergoes drastic change in its flow conditions. Aeration process and the forest in the downstream area filters the silt in the river.[10]

Chitakoot Falls is one of the two of the waterfalls located in the Kanger Valley National Park, the other is Tirathgarh falls.
    "</string>
<string name="gadiyamountain">"The Gadiya Mountain came into light at the time of Kandra dynasty. When the Kandra king Dharma Dev won the Kanker. He declared his capital on Gadhiya Mountain, which is a natural form of a fort. On the mountain there is a tank which never dries and fulfill by water throughout the year. One part of this tank is called as Sonai and the other part of this tank is called as Rupai. Actually Sonai and Rupai were the two daughters of Kandra king Dharma Dev. On the southern part of this tank there is a cave named Churi pagar. The entry of this cave is very much narrow. On any outer attack the King and his family lived safe in this cave. The space of the cave is able to sit 500 peoples inside. The exit door of this cave is towards west direction. In the south east part of Gadhiya mountain there is an other cave called Jogi cave. The length of this cave is 50 meters. In ancient time a lot of monks lives here alone time to time for there meditation. there is a small pond this cave. the water of this cave flows on the rock like a water fall. On the bottom of Gadhiya mountain the Doodh river flows. On Maha Shivratri there is a small festival celebrated on this mountain. On that day thousand of people climb on the mountain. Now there is a concrete leader available for climbing on the mountain."</string>
<string name="maitribhagh">"Maitri Bagh is a very good Zoo as well as a Park with Musical Fountain.
Maitri means Friendship and Bagh Means Garden. Maitri Bagh is really a "Friendship Garden" and was established as symbol of India USSR frienship.
Its was developed and maintained by Bhilai Steel Plant , SAIL. This is one of best picnic spot in Chhattisgarh.
There is a Pragrati Minar which gives a very beautiful top view of Zoo and Steel Plant.
The Zoo is open for 10:00 AM to 5:00 PM and park is open till 7:30 PM.
The time of musical fountain show is 7:00 PM only on Saturday and Sunday So best time to visit the zoo and park is 4:00 PM and the day is Saturday ( To avoid crowd).
Entrance Fee : 10 Rs.
Park and Zoo is closed on Monday.
About 20 minutes from the Bhilai Steel Plant, one can find the Maitri Bagh or the ‘Garden of Frienship’ built to commemorate the friendship between Indian and the Russian Government. This garden has been built and managed by the Bhilai Steel Plant. It is considered to one of the best hangout spots in the state of Chhattisgarh, enjoyed by people of all ages. It consists of a large zoo, beautiful lakes, gardens, musical fountain, a tall tower called the Pragati Minar, a toy train called ‘Maitri Express’ for the children. It is thus an amazing picnic spot, a must – visit with your family and friends. The lush greenery, shimmering musical fountain, flower beds and scenic locales attract tourists from far and wide. Adjacent to the garden, is Bhilai Water Works, providing water to the township.
    "</string>
<string name="rajpuriwaterfall">"Jashpur situated on the Northern part of Chhattisgarh, India is perfect for a leisurely weekend getaway. The Uraon tribal population and their small settlements lend a different charm to Jashpur. These tribals have their own folklore and tradition. There is nothing like watching a tribal dance on a moonlit night. Jashpur is replete with hilly terrain and forests in the Upper Ghats while the lower plain consists of sprawling Rivers and waterfalls. The Rivers, Caves and Waterfalls in Jashpur provides ample opportunities for angling, trekking and hiking. The path may not be smooth as in some of these places road construction is still in process. However the journey is rewarding in ways more than one. Take a leisurely stroll through the Rajpuri Waterfall to see the many facets of nature here.

Rajpuri Waterfall is one of the most frequented spots in Jashpur. It is also a popular picnic spots. The tribal villages in and around the place adds a different charm to the whole place. There is something haunting about the whole place. Very few tourists visit here. The rocky wall on the sides seems to be of prehistoric times and tells an ancient tale. Like many other places in Jashpur, even this has a story to tell and a popular folklore to back it. The place is located 60 kilometers from Jashpur main. You also have ample scope for fishing in Rajpuri Waterfall.`"</string>

</resources>
